<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 15:03:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Werewolves of Millers Hollow MOD: Predator (Chupacabra)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2013/02/12/the-werewolves-of-millers-hollow-mod-predator-chupacabra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 15:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2013/02/12/the-werewolves-of-millers-hollow-mod-predator-chupacabra/</guid>
      <description>This is a modification for the social deception game The Werewolves of Millers Hollow (also sometimes known as Werewolf, Mafia, and Witch Hunt).
Pick an unused card from the deck. I like the Witch (the orange card). Herein, this card is now known as the Predator (or Chupacabra, because it&amp;rsquo;s funnier). The Predator is an additional “non human”, and its goal is to hunt and kill off the Werewolves. The humans are indifferent and want to kill anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t a human (after all, it has no qualms about killing humans to find wolves).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towlr at N-Design Exhibit</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/21/towlr-at-n-design-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/21/towlr-at-n-design-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Towlr recently frustrated attendees at “N Design”, an art-game exhibit in Curitiba, Brazil. Very cool!
Here are some photos of the event.
On your left, take note of the bright eye burning red
Descriptions floating on the wall &amp;ndash; Very classy
Several other favorites were at the event, included a Rohrer game, a Terry Cavanagh game, and of course, Braid.
More details can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Smiles PC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/09/introducing-smiles-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 06:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/09/introducing-smiles-pc/</guid>
      <description>This is not what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to all year, but it is what I&amp;rsquo;m up to right now.
So, let&amp;rsquo;s introduce the project.
Officially, the project is named Smiles. Specifically though, the project&amp;rsquo;s working title is Smiles PC. Just as you&amp;rsquo;d expect, it&amp;rsquo;s Smiles the iPhone game for PC, Mac and Linux. Actually it&amp;rsquo;s more than that, but lets stick with this for now.
At it&amp;rsquo;s core, Smiles PC is about removing the dependencies of the iPhone from the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I make games to piss you off</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/11/i-make-games-to-piss-you-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 22:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/11/i-make-games-to-piss-you-off/</guid>
      <description>Slightly off topic today. Well, if you&amp;rsquo;re expecting mystery iPhone game news that is.
The weekend ended up being a little more slack-tastic that I&amp;rsquo;d hoped. Ludum Dare 12 after all, which always keeps me busy.
With only a couple hours left, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d throw something together quickly. Well, those couple hours went very well.
With so little time, I obviously couldn&amp;rsquo;t make anything extravagant. What I ended up with was a game best described as “a game designed to piss you off“.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplification</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/12/simplification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 04:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/12/simplification/</guid>
      <description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s an important direction and discussion for game design. Sure, as a gamer, I can handle complicated control schemes. I&amp;rsquo;ve done my time and held my own in hotkey crazy RTS&amp;rsquo;s, twitch FPS&amp;rsquo;s, and I can be pretty menacing in Tony Hawk. But most of these games aren&amp;rsquo;t getting any easier. I don&amp;rsquo;t even care to finish Tony Hawk&amp;rsquo;s Project 8, or the Underground games, because the things you need to do at the end are ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>