<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smiles on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/smiles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Smiles on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/smiles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Because We May Sale</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://toonormal.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/Atwx4_gCIAAQ5Hq.jpg-larg2e.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becausewemay.com&#34;&gt;Because We May&lt;/a&gt;, a grandiose cross platform mega sale is on right now. Android, iPad, iPhone, PC (Desura), and Blackberry Playbook versions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smileshd.com&#34;&gt;Smiles and Smiles HD&lt;/a&gt; are all heavily discounted and available for about $2. The sale ends June 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for Kindle now Available!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/11/09/smiles-for-kindle-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 23:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/11/09/smiles-for-kindle-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Hey look what finally came out!
Here’s a video.
Without spoiling it, I’m very happy with how it’s selling so far. 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One more prize for the road</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 14:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Progress on the tech for my upcoming game “Alone, The” has been a little slow the past couple weeks, due to Ludum Dare, a nightmare of server issues (both LD and my own), and my upcoming move (OMG THAT’S RIGHT NOW). I have some great news to share though:
 TransGaming Announces Winner of the $10,000 GameTree Developer Competition: Developer’s Choice Award Developers from around the world have their say: Smiles HD takes home the prize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nope, not this time</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</guid>
      <description>No sir. Do not pass go, do not collect $50,000.
However! All is not lost!
I am still eligible for a the $10k “Developers Choice” award, which means you, you developers! Visit GameTreeDeveloper.com and cast your vote (For Smiles HD). 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I might win something&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</guid>
      <description>The latest in the world of Mike, I might win something again.
I’m less than an hour away from finding out if it’s true, so here’s me killing minutes as I wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Indie Indie Conversation</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! I figured now was a good time to talk about a project I’ve been involved with for the past couple months now. Something we like to call, the Indie Indie Conversation. The conversation is a YouTube channel shared amongst a group of indie game developers where we talk about what we do, the challenges, and the lifestyle of creating games independently for a living.
I’ve personally failed many attempts at starting a regular video log here on my blog, and in retrospect that may have been the uncomfortable feeling of “talking to a wall”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last Smiles Trailer</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/25/the-last-smiles-trailer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 18:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/25/the-last-smiles-trailer/</guid>
      <description>I did miss my June 23rd target date, but with good reason: I started on computer upgrades and setting up my new Laptop early. 😀
But yes, as you approach the end of something, there are always things you forget about that still need to be done.
Like this, a Computer and TV-System appropriate trailer for Smiles HD (i.e. without entire screen rotating):
As you can see, that is now done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/ending-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/ending-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Yes, you read that right. It is ending. For real.
June 23rd is the 3 year anniversary of Smiles (as in, starting the game). I have finished every single port of the game that I had planned on doing (except console ports, both I decided to abort); Some are still in submission or need of final packaging. Days away now.
Today is June 15th, a whole week away from the anniversary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for Kindle</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/smiles-for-kindle-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/smiles-for-kindle-2/</guid>
      <description>Speaking of better, here’s the final gameplay trailer for Kindle Smiles:
That is submitted and in the queue now. Should be available in the Amazon Kindle store soon.
BONUS!
I recorded a brief “making-of” video, showing how recording the footage for the above video would look.
Now that Smiles is finally winding down, I’m hoping to do more little things like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So much for that</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/so-much-for-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/so-much-for-that/</guid>
      <description>Hey, well that didn’t work. Smiles for WP7 after a couple weeks.
Or according to my data: 9 trial downloads, and 1 sale since. There was some twitter talking, some retweets by fellow devs, but there’s practically no noticeable spike.
Ah well, so much for that. On to bigger better things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOS: Save our Smiles (for WP7)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/05/24/sos-save-our-smiles-for-wp7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 20:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/05/24/sos-save-our-smiles-for-wp7/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I just received a 2nd e-mail informing me my “Microsoft Windows Phone Marketplace developer account” yearly membership needs to be renewed. That costs $99 USD, and I think I paid $129 CAD.
I made this game (Smiles), and I paid a friend to work with me to port it to Windows Phone 7:
It was available on launch day for Windows Phone 7. Looks like a pretty well made game, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen and Smiles Drop available on the Ovi Store!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/06/smiles-zen-and-smiles-drop-available-on-the-ovi-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 09:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/06/smiles-zen-and-smiles-drop-available-on-the-ovi-store/</guid>
      <description>Looks like the Symbian^3 versions of the game went live this morning in the Ovi store.
A 5-star positive review of both games so far. Excellent!
I’m writing up a nice long post (to follow) about the new game. Hopefully finished soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles and Smiles HD for Android now available!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/05/smiles-and-smiles-hd-for-android-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 21:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/05/smiles-and-smiles-hd-for-android-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Finally! Go take a look!
https://market.android.com/developer?pub=Sykhronics+Entertainment
To say the Android port has was the most requested would be an understatement. I sent messages to the list of starred people in my e-mailbox, everyone that ever asked about the Android version… I hope I got everyone. It feels good to finally have this covered. Ahhh!
There are 2 versions of the game available. Content wise they’re totally the same, but the difference is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike and Middleware</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/04/mike-and-middleware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/04/mike-and-middleware/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been making games for a really long time now, but one thing I’ve found myself rather resilient to was letting myself use Middleware. By Middleware, I mean 3rd party libraries. It’s funny since I always highly recommend that people use it (to save RIDICULOUS amounts of time), but I myself am just a really slow adopter of it.
SDL is one of few long-time 3rd party libraries I use. It lets me write my game code against the PC, Mac, Linux, and a few mobiles including Palm/HP’s webOS and Nokia’s Maemo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for Kindle</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/01/smiles-for-kindle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 16:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/04/01/smiles-for-kindle/</guid>
      <description>Happy April 1st!
To start, my thing to make you laugh.
I’ll be finishing this up in the coming weeks. I had to prioritize some stuff ahead of it due at the end March (another reason I’ve been so quiet post GDC). There was also a faux pas on my part, but nothing too big… I just have to drive down to the US border and activate a 2nd gen Kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to crank it to&amp;#8230; you get the idea</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/01/04/time-to-crank-it-to-you-get-the-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 19:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/01/04/time-to-crank-it-to-you-get-the-idea/</guid>
      <description>2011 is here! The IGF finalists have been announced, CES is upon us, and GDC is less than 2 months away. I always have a hard time following up epic posts like the last one. So with this, my third attempt (ahem), I’m going to try to be more to the point: My plans for the year.
First, the Mac App Store launches on Thursday… I wonder if Mike did something for that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toggling Windows</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/02/toggling-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 04:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/02/toggling-windows/</guid>
      <description>Added a toggle button for Windowed and Fullscreen today, and made it actually work. I also did some tweaking of the icons around the edge of the screen (pushed them higher, made the outlines more consistent).
The About/Credits screen icon is now a speech bubble (was a “?”, so not to confuse it with the help menu). Just a few more tweaks to go before I dive in to Android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achievement Unlock Sound Effect</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/01/achievement-unlock-sound-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 13:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/01/achievement-unlock-sound-effect/</guid>
      <description>I am a regular twitter user. I run a client (twhirl) in the corner of my right monitor, so for me it works like a weird combination of an IM client and RSS reader.
A couple days ago, I caught glance of this request from Noel Llopis (developer of Flower Garden, Dr. Seuss’ Lorax Garden, and the upcoming Casey’s Contraptions).
That’s a good question. As far as I know there’s no real “standard” achievement sound (unless you want to rip-off Microsoft).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eighty Five Percent</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/30/eighty-five-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 03:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/30/eighty-five-percent/</guid>
      <description>Alright, time to get back in to the routine.
It’s been two weeks since the last post. Last week became an impromptu holiday for me — I am a Canadian living in Canada, but I deal mostly with US companies, so American Thanksgiving seemed safe.
The week prior was busy though. I sent off the initial version of Smiles HD for the Mac App Store. It still sits in the approval queue, but I’m there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles in 64 bits</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/13/smiles-in-64-bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 02:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/13/smiles-in-64-bits/</guid>
      <description>So I spent the evening getting Smiles working in 64bit Linux (Ubuntu 10.10) as well as the Mac. Here are the results:
And the Mac again:
And a closeup of the processes section:
Getting it working on the Mac wasn’t really necessary, but I really like Xcode’s debugging tools. They made tracing the issue very straightforward. I had two VNC windows going almost constantly, as I’d make changes on the Workstation PC, commit to SVN, and sync on both the Mac and the Zotac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu on the Zotac</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/12/ubuntu-on-the-zotac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 20:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/12/ubuntu-on-the-zotac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I get to the meat of this post, last night I finished my “early” Mac App Store TODO list. I *COULD* submit it now, but there’s a bug with submissions. My iPad version is called Smiles HD, and so will be the Mac App Store version. Right now the names conflict, so I have to wait until this is fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now it’s “done”. I sent the binary to some friends to double-check compatibility. So while I wait, it’s time to get on other ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notably, my Mac binary is only a 32bit Intel binary. My source &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; compile in 64bit mode, but runs in to issues. Smiles isn’t a game that needs 64bit addressing, but unlike Windows and OSX, 64bit Linux doesn’t support 32bit applications (not stock at least). So one of my next portability challenges is making my Smiles codebase support 64bit Intel and AMD chips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* * *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from my Workstation PC and Macs, I have a lot of Netbooks. The Netbooks are what I usually use for Linux development. Unfortunately, all the Netbooks I currently have don’t support 64bit instructions (the current generation Intel Atom CPU’s do).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I ordered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zotacusa.com/zotac-mag-hd-nd01.html&#34;&gt;one of these&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;Zotac MAG&lt;/strong&gt; Nettop PC. For about $250 CAD (with a rebate), it’s a dual core Atom 330 running at 1.6 GHz, 2 GB of RAM, 160 GB Hard Drive, with an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nvidia_Ion&#34;&gt;NVidia ION&lt;/a&gt; chipset (GeForce 9400M). I’m technically lacking an AMD and ATI test machine, but I do have one of each elsewhere I can turn to if I run in to problems (both running Windows).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version I ordered isn’t the most up to date (original NVidia ION, last year’s Dual Core Atom), which is on purpose. This is both a development and a test machine, and if I can buy one for $250, so will other people looking for a low cost PC… not that an NVidia 9400M is anything to shake a stick at either. This gives me a good cross section of graphics hardware I can test in Linux (Intel GMA on the Netbooks, NVidia on the Nettop).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I purchased my first Netbook a couple years back (an Acer Aspire One), I started a secondary blog where I recorded all my setup notes, thoughts, and learnings (new word!!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aspireonedev.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://aspireonedev.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here’s an extra little blog I created to share the super technical and super nuance details of a little project of mine. Turning a stock 8GB SSD Acer Aspire One running Linpus Linux in to an ideal lightweight coding machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than anything, it was a blog about me learning to use Linux for development. I know a lot more about working inside Linux now, but posts of mine like this I found extremely helpful when I started doing things like Moblin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aspireonedev.blogspot.com/2008/10/intalling-console-applications.html&#34;&gt;http://aspireonedev.blogspot.com/2008/10/intalling-console-applications.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the remainder of this blog post will be me walking through the setup steps taken to set up this new machine for development, and get my 32bit makefile running and building code. In retrospect, the recorded setup details should be identical no matter the CPU architecture (32bit or 64bit, though this was me doing it 64bit style).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As expected, twas the Cache</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/10/as-expected-twas-the-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2010 20:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/10/as-expected-twas-the-cache/</guid>
      <description>Not much to say or show, just that the performance problem was due to the textures being larger than the texture cache.
As it is now, on my Mac mini the game runs at under 8% CPU usage in the menus and Zen, and under 10% in Drop. The largest texture is 1024×1024, DXT5 compressed (4:1, or 1 MB). Before it was 1024×1024 uncompressed 32bit RGBA (1:1, or 4 MB). That either means the GMA 950 in these older Mac’s has 1 MB of cache, or perhaps 2 MB (I didn’t check with 16bit RGBA textures, but it’s unlikely).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macs and Cheese</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/07/macs-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 01:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/07/macs-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>This week I’ve been downloading updates for all my tools. Linux distros, as well as Apple tools and OS updates. Yesterday was spent trying to get a 64bit version of Ubuntu running on my Media Center PC (i.e. my old dual core AMD workstation PC, now hooked up to the projector). My initial attempt of installing it to a USB key didn’t work, but I did eventually get it working using WUBI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimize and Exit buttons in a screen layout</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/04/minimize-and-exit-buttons-in-a-screen-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 17:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/04/minimize-and-exit-buttons-in-a-screen-layout/</guid>
      <description>Going through my Smiles HD TODO/Wishlist, one thing I’ve been meaning to add to the game for a long time was a minimize button. The game runs on several multitasking OS’s, but your only option up until now was to exit. Now, if the OS supports it, it can be suspended in to the background with just a click.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for PC&amp;#8217;s, Mac&amp;#8217;s and Linux&amp;#8217;s Month (and Droids?)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/03/smiles-for-pcs-macs-and-linuxs-month-and-droids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 08:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/03/smiles-for-pcs-macs-and-linuxs-month-and-droids/</guid>
      <description>Well alright. I agreed to do a little contract gig back during the summer that finally caught up with me, so the past couple weeks were spent on that. Yesterday we finally finished and submitted that, so I’m free to work on what’s really important: Smiles HD for computers!
Wait… what!?
Okay, well I still do have my new-game scheduling plans detailed in the last post, but I’ll be slightly delaying that start time yet again, but not by much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Schedule Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/16/future-schedule-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 18:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/16/future-schedule-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It’s now half way through the month, and progress on my “October Game” is minimal to say the least. I suppose that was to be expected, since I did have several things to finish this month. My week-days have been filled with various tasks, leaving only weekends to work on this new thing. Next week I’ll be busy with my “1 more thing”, leaving me the last week of October for a final crunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles in the Zune/WP7 Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/15/smiles-in-the-zune-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 21:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/15/smiles-in-the-zune-store/</guid>
      <description>I quite like the aesthetics of the Zune WP7 Marketplace. It’s hard to see, but the background is this large panoramic image I whipped up. The panorama looks pretty sweet on the phone. Whomever was responsible for the Zune and WP7 phone graphic design, it’s some fine work. Hats off to you sir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for WP7, the PR so far</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/13/smiles-for-wp7-the-pr-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 21:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/13/smiles-for-wp7-the-pr-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Since the summer I’ve been chatting with Microsoft about bringing Smiles to Windows Phone 7.
In early September, I was invited to an event “Windows Phone 7 Blogger Night” in Toronto.
More photos can be found here: http://blogs.msdn.com/b/cdndevs/…/toronto.aspx
* * *
In addition, I make a brief appearance in this video.
http://blogs.msdn.com/b/cdndevs/…/canadian-windows-phone-developers.aspx
Heh, this might be one of my worst appearances on video (Mr. Shiny forehead), but fortunately it’s very quick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles &amp;#8211; Coming to Windows Phone 7</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/12/smiles-coming-to-windows-phone-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/12/smiles-coming-to-windows-phone-7/</guid>
      <description>So here’s that news: Smiles is coming to Windows Phone 7!
Here’s proof.
And here’s a snap of the game running on a completely different Windows Phone device, an LG.
I love it when code runs on many different devices. 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A (rough) AppUp porting guide</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/31/a-rough-appup-porting-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2010 18:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/31/a-rough-appup-porting-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the items on my &lt;em&gt;seemingly infinite&lt;/em&gt; TODO list is to write an article about how to port an iPhone game to AppUp. Another item is to rework my blog layout and list all the actually useful content written here. I’ve yet to do either, but I think I have here a good compromise for the 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do a-lot of emailing, and this past week I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lazy8studios.com/&#34;&gt;had a chat with a fellow developer&lt;/a&gt; who wanted some advice on porting his game. I sometimes forget about the hours of work that went in to figuring out the the right combination of Unix tools, Windows tools, cross platform libraries, and how to smash them together until they make something that actually works. So I sent him a very &lt;em&gt;to the point&lt;/em&gt; list of things that I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime after that, I realized I should just post that e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final mobile port (for now)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/06/05/the-final-mobile-port-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 01:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/06/05/the-final-mobile-port-for-now/</guid>
      <description>I actually finished on Sunday, but the final mobile port of Smiles is now sent. The port is for Samsung’s Bada mobile platform. I was pleasantly surprised how straight forward it was to get things up and running there. The system API is very much like a C++ version of Apple’s ObjC iPhoneOS API. The whole endeavor took no more than 4 days worth of work.
So done!
I will continue to support the existing plethora of ports as needed, but now it’s time to switch gears, and get going on the new project!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netbook Smiles updates sent</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/29/netbook-smiles-updates-sent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 13:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/29/netbook-smiles-updates-sent/</guid>
      <description>So finally, Smiles 1.1 for Netbooks (The Intel AppUp Center) has been submitted. Also, though Moblin Netbook Smiles was submitted last week, it came back with a very minor issue. That is now fixed, and sent as well. So Netbook Smiles == all done.
I have 1 last mobile port I’m doing, Samsung Bada. Again, Google wont let Canadians make Google Checkout Merchant accounts, so Android and NACL Smiles ports will be pending that, and a good motivator for each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles on Nokia N900 (Maemo)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/27/smiles-on-nokia-n900-maemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 10:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/27/smiles-on-nokia-n900-maemo/</guid>
      <description>The latest in the seemingly endless stream of ports (the first of the two implied quicker ports I’m doing… though the 2nd one is sounding not so quick after all).
The N900 is a Linux (Maemo) based device, so I was literally able to pick up where I finished the Moblin (Linux) ports.
Admittedly, it was a bit of a scary port, since I was only initially able to get the game to do about 10 fps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greatest Port Ever (heh)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/23/greatest-port-ever-heh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 18:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/23/greatest-port-ever-heh/</guid>
      <description>Realistic? Heck no! But totally awesome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Poster Boy</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/21/vnc-poster-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 09:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/21/vnc-poster-boy/</guid>
      <description>Heh, I certainly wasn’t expecting this.
RealVNC has a rotating twitter quotes on their front page, and it seems I’m now part of the rotation.
And yes, that is a real quote; I do think VNC is awesome. Admittedly, I’ve been using UltraVNC on my PC’s recently, though I do run their iPhone client. 😉
Thanks for the tip Adam.
– – –
I FINALLY submitted my Moblin (Linux) AppUp port of Smiles late last night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Fire Porting</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/19/rapid-fire-porting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 06:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/19/rapid-fire-porting/</guid>
      <description>I have a goal of switching my focus entirely to a new project starting in July, which is about 6 weeks away. My 30th birthday is the 6th, so my folks have been joking that’ll be my gift to myself. Happy Birthday Mike, you can do something else now… heh.
So to make that happen, I need to power through my list of pending platforms I want to cover, before back-burner’ing the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging for 5 years now&amp;#8230; wuh, really!?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/09/blogging-for-5-years-now-wuh-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 02:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/09/blogging-for-5-years-now-wuh-really/</guid>
      <description>I wont pretend this blog features much quality content, but it seems I’ve been filling it with nonsense for 5 years now (started May 1st 2005). So wow!
Completely unrelated, yet an appropriate way to celebrate, I now have an image at the top of the site. Wow ‘eh? Now I am a whole 2 steps away from the default WordPress theme (the 1st step was widening the layout).
The past week I’ve been busy with a variety of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles running on the Palm Pre, plus other things</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/23/smiles-running-on-the-palm-pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 01:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/23/smiles-running-on-the-palm-pre/</guid>
      <description>One of the sessions I saw at GDC this year was Palm’s talk about their new PDK (i.e. their native SDK). The promise was a Linux based mobile device featuring SDL and OpenGL ES. Since my Windows and Linux code base also uses SDL and OpenGL, that certainly caught my attention. In theory, all I need to do is just recompile my Linux version with their tools and I’m done, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automobiles, Interviews, all Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 22:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</guid>
      <description>To say 2010 has been a busy year would be an understatement.
While we were all waiting for Apple to confirm the existence of the iPad, I was busy tweaking, improving, and porting my game Smiles to a bunch of new platforms. The most significant port by far was to Netbook PCs for Intel’s AppUp Center, a brand new App Store coming soon to Netbooks everywhere.
To say Intel and AppUp have been good to me, that would be another understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD bug list (and launch day thoughts)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/03/smiles-hd-bug-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 22:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/03/smiles-hd-bug-list/</guid>
      <description>Wow! So that was iPad launch day.
I’ll talk a little more about the “day 1 FREE” experiment after some results. Just before disappearing, the game was sitting at #60 in the Top FREE Apps (#13 Top FREE Games). Earlier today, I caught it at #55. Anyways, I said I wasn’t going to talk about this!
Like many other developers, I shipped the game to Apple for launch day without actually testing it on a real device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD is now #100!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/02/smiles-hd-is-now-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 22:23:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/02/smiles-hd-is-now-100/</guid>
      <description>It took all night, but Smiles HD has finally made it on to the Top 100 FREE games chart!

I couldn’t have asked for a better way to end the night. Thanks everyone! Keep spreading the word, and have fun with Smiles HD on your iPads!
http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/smiles-hd/id364871736?mt=8
Remember: Smiles HD is FREE *ONLY* until the end of the day April 3rd! Regular price, $4.99. I think you’ll agree, it’s worth at least that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD FREE for iPad Launch Day</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/02/smiles-hd-free-for-ipad-launch-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 21:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/02/smiles-hd-free-for-ipad-launch-day/</guid>
      <description>Well it seems I didn’t make any of the launch day “Featured” spots, but I still want to make a splash. So I introduce to you my CRAZIEST idea yet.
Smiles HD, regular price $4.99 is FREE April 3rd!

http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/smiles-hd/id364871736?mt=8
At of this writing, I’m #27 in the top games, literally 1 spot below the actual Top 100 Apps. So very close!
I’ll be up for an hour or so, before getting some sleep prior to my trip to the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD is GOLD!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/31/smiles-hd-is-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 20:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/31/smiles-hd-is-gold/</guid>
      <description>A long day of waiting, but now that I have you my little green dot, it can finally end.
Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD &amp;#8211; Gameplay Videos!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/29/smiles-hd-gameplay-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 23:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/29/smiles-hd-gameplay-videos/</guid>
      <description>Oh hey. Like literally an hour or two after that big epic blog post of mine, Apple let us know we could submit early. So I crunched the game together and did exactly that.
Here’s some final video footage of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD &amp;#8211; Development Video &amp;#8211; a typical game</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/23/smiles-hd-video-a-typical-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 09:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/23/smiles-hd-video-a-typical-game/</guid>
      <description>Here’s an early development video of Smiles HD. The video shows a typical game of Drop at the Normal difficulty (typical for me at least).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramping up for iPad: Smiles HD</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</guid>
      <description>Alright! The iPad is coming soon, as is a brand new version of Smiles.
As we speak I’m putting the finishing touches on Smiles HD, the all new higher resolution and slightly redesigned iPhone game coming soon to the iPad.
Now, in the eyes of Apple I’m nobody special. So like many of you, I’ll be heading down to my local Apple store on launch day to pick me up an iPad… with one slight difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike the Multi-Winner and GDC Champion</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</guid>
      <description>So, holy cow! GDC was absolutely insane! I almost don’t know where to start, but lets start from the beginning.
First thing first, I won again!!
Yes, as if winning a free car wasn’t enough, I also won a free trip to GDC. So Intel ended up covering my flight, putting me up in a fancy hotel, gave me some spending money, treating me to dinner, AND giving me nearly front row seats to a San Jose Sharks hockey game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalizing your GDC pass</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 22:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</guid>
      <description>Ordinarily, greeting someone by glancing at their chest might be seen as a little rude (especially a lady), but at GDC it’s encouraged! Yes I’m talking about the passes, not making a pass.
The passes do a good job of helping you connect a face to a name, and even a company, but you don’t always know who made or represents what. GDC passes include a relatively large pocket, so you could either make something to insert behind your name card, or cover the pass with some strategically placed stickers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Different GDC (for me)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</guid>
      <description>So last year, I was an IGF Mobile finalist. This little game of mine stood alongside iPhone favorites like Edge and Fieldrunners, vying for the “Best Mobile Game” award. And if I had won, … well, I have no idea. Even just being a finalist has been great for me, so I’d image it would have been MORE great. 😉
That was 2009, and this is 2010.
This year started out as my “low key” and “quiet” GDC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &amp;#8220;Intel is awesome&amp;#8221; post</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/03/the-intel-is-awesome-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/03/the-intel-is-awesome-post/</guid>
      <description>So hey. Back in December I finished up a 1.0 port of Smiles for Netbooks, and sent it to Intel by their early contest deadline.
And hey, guess what?
Link here.
Second place! That’s awesome. 😀
So hey, what does 2nd place actually mean?
Wow. So I guess I’ve got a pretty good story now when mingling at GDC. 😀
I’ll post some photos once it arrives.
Woohoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD for iPad</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/29/smiles-hd-for-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 00:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/29/smiles-hd-for-ipad/</guid>
      <description>I’m sure this will surprise no one, but yes I’ll be releasing Smiles HD for iPad.
The iPad port will be based on my current Smiles code running on Netbooks and some Windows Mobile devices (Samsung Omnia II), but I’m in the process of adding several more enhancements on top of that. I’ll dive in to more of the specifics as iPad launch gets closer.
The biggest different between iPhone Smiles and my current code is I’ve squared the playfield (was 9×8, now 8×8) and added rotation buttons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles for Windows Available&amp;#8230; sort of!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/08/smiles-for-windows-available-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/08/smiles-for-windows-available-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>As part of Intel’s new AppUp Center launched at CES yesterday, Smiles is now available for select Windows PC’s of the XP and 7 varieties.
http://www.intel.com/consumer/products/appup.htm
The store is very new and beta. It’s designed specifically for Netbooks and the OEMs that make them, but is freely available to for everyone to test and purchase from. Me personally, I had to install .NET 3.5 and .NET 3.5 Service Pack 1 on my Aspire One to make it work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike&amp;#8217;s 2009</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 19:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</guid>
      <description>So wow. That’s finally it for 2009. Like doing taxes ever year, I feel a special sort of obligation that I write some sort of retrospective, especially after such an eventful year as this one. Far more awesome than taxes. 😉
I wasn’t sure where to start, so I ended up categorizing aspects of the year. I’ll free form rant about each topic as I come to it.
Let’s begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles New Years Sale (and more)!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/30/smiles-new-years-sale-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 07:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/30/smiles-new-years-sale-and-more/</guid>
      <description>It’s that time of year again. We did it last year, and we’re doing it again for 2010.
The New Year App Blowout.
www.newyearappblowout.com
Yours truly has put all 3 Smiles games on for New Years. Grab it while it’s cheap.
  
Smiles Zen – $0.99 (Was $1.99)
Smiles Drop – $0.99 (Was $1.99)
Smiles – $1.99 (Was $2.99) – Contains both Zen and Drop
Of course, Smiles isn’t the only thing on sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was 4th place</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/23/i-was-4th-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/23/i-was-4th-place/</guid>
      <description>As the title suggests, I came 4th place with Smiles Zen (in Italian).
I imagine the English versions will be available soon. Samsung’s approval department might be taking xmas off though. 😉
Happy Holidays folks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Port</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/21/another-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/21/another-port/</guid>
      <description>Well, I can relax now. 🙂
I have the results back from the Samsung contest, but I can’t say how that went … yet. There’s supposed to be a proper winners announcement deal on SamsungApps Thursday, so if I have anything to add, I’ll do it then.
So that’s one thing off my mind.
The other thing off my mind is Intel’s contest. Netbook ports were due today, the same day as the results for Samsung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Port and a Compo</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/14/a-port-and-a-compo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 20:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/12/14/a-port-and-a-compo/</guid>
      <description>Wow. To say the last 3 weeks have been busy would be an understatement.
First of all, I ported Smiles to a new phone. The Samsung Omnia II, a Windows Mobile phone with a beautiful amoled screen and a custom GPU. Some photos.
For those keeping score, the game unfortunately runs a little slow on the Omnia II. It’s definitely playable, but the GPU is no PowerVR SGX. I did what I could in the time I had, optimized my shaders and all that, but it’s what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stocked and Loaded</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/26/stocked-and-loaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/26/stocked-and-loaded/</guid>
      <description>An intense month of work awaits. Crunch time, and then some!
Early/Mid last week, I spec’d out the plan for my time between now and GDC. Quite a busy schedule, with a lot of really cool things coming up. Smiles stuff, and a quick collaboration with a friend, which I’ll talk more about later. I should have plenty to talk about with my internet colleagues in March.
But the icing on the cake was a development Wednesday/Thursday of last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Annoying) Differences between Visual Studio and GCC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/15/annoying-differences-between-visual-studio-and-gcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 19:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/15/annoying-differences-between-visual-studio-and-gcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or in other words, awesome C an C++ language features you’ll learn to love in GCC, that’ll break your heart if you ever have to use Visual Studio. 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a list I collected whilst getting my Smiles PC code to compile with Visual Studio 2008. Most have no equivalent in Visual Studio, but one simply has a slightly different syntax (compatible too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As before, long and technical. Hit the link if you’re up for the challenge. You’ve been warned. 😀&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Smiles PC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/09/introducing-smiles-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 06:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/09/introducing-smiles-pc/</guid>
      <description>This is not what I’ve been up to all year, but it is what I’m up to right now.
So, let’s introduce the project.
Officially, the project is named Smiles. Specifically though, the project’s working title is Smiles PC. Just as you’d expect, it’s Smiles the iPhone game for PC, Mac and Linux. Actually it’s more than that, but lets stick with this for now.
At it’s core, Smiles PC is about removing the dependencies of the iPhone from the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final cross promotion and freebie changes</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/08/final-cross-promotion-and-freebie-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 04:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/08/final-cross-promotion-and-freebie-changes/</guid>
      <description>As planned, Smiles Zen 1.3 and Smiles Drop 1.3 were sent late Friday night (technically 5 AM the next day). I made the mentioned addition of arrows after discovering some people didn’t realize you could click on the icon. Here’s a snap of that from the iPhone build on the PC.
I had some friends look at this screen, and got a good reaction from the “love hearts”, so I made a similar change to free version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Cross promotion in Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/06/video-cross-promotion-in-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 18:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/06/video-cross-promotion-in-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Here’s something I hope to start doing more often. Technically, I’ve been hoping to actually start all year. Short development video logs.
Today’s video is a demonstration of the cross promotion features in Smiles Zen and Smiles Drop. Inspiration hit last night, and I added something amusing to it I’d thought I’d share.
Both builds should go out tonight. I’ll be adding a pair of arrows beside the icon, just so it’s even clearer that you can click on it right here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross promotion in Zen and Drop</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/02/cross-promotion-in-zen-and-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 18:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/02/cross-promotion-in-zen-and-drop/</guid>
      <description>Smiles 1.3 is already in the Apple queue, but not Zen and Drop yet. Something “new” in 1.3 is that I removed the “how to play music” instructions from the game. This used to be in the upper right corner of the screen. The description used to say you could “double tap” the home button to bring up music playback, but it seems that was wrong on the iPhones and 3rd gen iPods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen &amp;#8220;FREE ZEN WEEKEND&amp;#8221; download stats</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/01/smiles-zen-free-download-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 13:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/01/smiles-zen-free-download-stats/</guid>
      <description>I figure there’s no reason not to share these.
Smiles Zen‘s “FREE ZEN WEEKEND” download statistics:
 1022 – Thursday October 29th (started at noon)
  3544 – Friday October 30th
  1826 – Saturday October 31st
  1361 – Sunday November 1st
  144 – Monday November 2nd (ended at 1 AM)
 The 29th was a fraction of a day. I flipped the switch roughly around noon, which kicked in about 4 hours later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles 1 Year Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/10/30/smiles-1-year-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 23:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/10/30/smiles-1-year-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the 1 year anniversary of the launch of Smiles.
…
Yeah, it’s been that long already.
This weekend I’m giving Smiles Zen away for FREE. Also, I’ve discounting Smiles to $1.99 to reflect the price. I guess that’s how we celebrate 1 year on iPhone. 😉
In other news, Smiles 1.3 is on the way. I discovered a graphics performance bug on the newer iPhones and iPods (SGX), so that is now fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles on sale for 99 cents</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/08/27/smiles-on-sale-for-99-cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 22:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/08/27/smiles-on-sale-for-99-cents/</guid>
      <description>The title says it all. Finally, after 10 months in the App Store, I’ve decided to try out the infamous 99 cent iPhone price with Smiles.
I sent an early pre-release note to some of the iPhone press, as well as my twitter. So far it’s been picked up by Touch Arcade which is always a good place to start.
I’m hopeful. The new trailer is out there in the wild now, and-a… now we wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trailer and a compo</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/08/25/a-trailer-and-a-compo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 23:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/08/25/a-trailer-and-a-compo/</guid>
      <description>Yes yes, I’m awfully quiet. What else is new?
Let me tell you.
First things first, a brand new trailer for Smiles.
Why does Smiles need a new trailer? I’ll tell you when you’re older.
This ended up taking a couple weeks longer than I’d hoped it would (spontaneous summer vacation?), but it’s done. The new trailer combines the tidbits dropped in the last post (mushroom animation, new logo), some gameplay footage, and a nice audio track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Mushrooms and Logo Tests</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</guid>
      <description>Been caught up with a number of things. Here’s one I’m rather proud of, an animated Smiles mushroom animation.
Click for 400k animated gif
Animated in ToonBoom Studio.
Something else, an updated Sykhronics Logo animation.
That one is me goofing off in Sony Vegas.
Fun fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The book is real, and more</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/06/15/the-book-is-real-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 17:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/06/15/the-book-is-real-and-more/</guid>
      <description>First on the agenda, the book is real.

As you can see above, my three complimentary copies showed up in the mail today. Word from the Dread Pirate himself (i.e. Lead Author/Tech Reviewer) is the books should be en route, if not already arriving at book stores all over the place. After all, the guy in Canada got his. 😉
– – – – –
Next, a Smiles update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The shelf-life of Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 14:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Smiles has been available for nearly 6 months in the App Store now. From the stories you may have heard, not all iPhone titles necessarily do well. But if you consider that the game was developed by one person in 4 months, it lives under the charts, and has only 1 Apple mention to it’s name, it’s actually done alright. I’m hardly “rolling in the dough”, but I can make ends meet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Statistics at GDC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/07/smiles-statistics-at-gdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 22:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/07/smiles-statistics-at-gdc/</guid>
      <description>For GDC, I decided to make a special version of Smiles. On the surface it would look like the Lite version (Free Smiles), except I re-enabled statistic tracking and high scores.
Here is how the visitors at my IGF kiosk did.
General Statistics
Total Time Played: 7 hours, 39 minutes
Games Played: 131
Zen Statistics
Total Time Playing: 4 hour, 12 minutes
Games Played: 78
Games Won: 33
Total Moves: 2640</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GDC and IGF Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 06:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Just a few hours ago I could barely move. Nearly crawling my way out of bed to attack the day (ahem… night), after the long flight home.
I’ve since returned to my regular routine of pacing around my studio (i.e. basement), between moments of awe e-mailing and ranting everywhere it seems appropriate (forums, twitter). As I exhausted all those wonderful forms of communication, it seemed to be right time to start the required retrospective post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Friday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 20:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</guid>
      <description>Friday was the short day. Wednesday and Thursday we exhibited 10-6, where Friday was 10-3. Went back to the hotel and vegged that day, before heading back out to hang with the Fantastic Contraption guys.
My neighbors were the Secret Exit guys. I ended up spending a bulk of the show goofing off with Tuukka, an artist on Zen Bound. The Secret Exit guys refer to him as the “prankster” of the bunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 01:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>First day of exhibiting. I have to say, I’m exhausted. Feet ached, and limped a bit throughout the day, but I loved it.
Here’s a few photos of the completed setup.

And a little closer.

I’m sharing a hotel with Phil Hassey of Galcon fame, and he had an amusing idea about creating some cheap signage. Hilighers and posterboard. At his booth he has a nicely done caracture of his goat Cuzco with a very supermarket-like sign advertising his sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Live from San Fransisco, it’s… me.
As you may or may not have heard, I didn’t win. But that’s alright, I’m still here to exhibit.
We’re sharing booth space with the IGF main competition entrants, which is great. That way, when people come to see the cool IGF games, they’ll find us too. Here’s my slice.

Other cool stuff, Apple put up a page of us IGF Mobile entries. Very awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspects of Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/28/aspects-of-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 23:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/28/aspects-of-smiles/</guid>
      <description>The first step with Smiles was to up the art resolution. That way, I could cleanly resize to any resolution below 4x the iPhone (1920×1280).
Unfortunately, double and quadruple iPhone res are not practical resolutions. Double iPhone will work windowed on most desktop LCD and 720p screens (960×640), and quadruple in a window fits on a 30″ Dell or Apple Cinema display, but we could do better.
Also, not all screens are the same shape, but the solution isn’t too difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/23/evolving-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 07:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/23/evolving-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Alright, I don’t see a reason not to talk about this publicly. So if I’m a good boy, I’ll be walking through my process of up-scaling, converting, and porting Smiles as it happens. Ideally, I’d like to have the game available for all 3 desktop platforms (Windows, Mac, Linux).
Quickly, Smiles is an IGF Mobile nominated collection of puzzle games for iPhone. You can learn more about the game at smiles-game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles in HD?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/21/smiles-in-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 06:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/21/smiles-in-hd/</guid>
      <description>Totally a tease. Click it if you dare! 🙂

(400k JPEG Version, 1 MB Lossless PNG Version)
Rebuilt the texture atlas’ for the weather and vegetables tilesets, and resized the majority of the in game assets. 3x’d the iPhone res instead of 4x’d, as that would be far too huge.
Art is large enough for 1080p, but the game needs numerous changes to properly support the new aspect ratio(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cheerfully Blunt Road Map</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 01:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</guid>
      <description>Alright, so the clock says it’s Friday now. According to my whiteboard, that’s 29 days before I leave for the Game Developers Conference. Between now and then, I have a few commitments to take care of. Possibly a 2nd draft for my writing engagement, jury (selection?) duty, in addition to IGF preparations. It’s also an important turning point for Smiles as a product and a brand. Lets talk about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Smiles, Part 0</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 04:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</guid>
      <description>I know my track record for completing a blog series is pretty lousy, but this one should be easier. I kept a personal log with pictures during the development of Smiles, so most of the work is done for me. I just need need to go through it and regurgitate my notes.
To start, I’m going to give a bit of insight in to what happened when I stopped writing my Engines, Names and Evolution blog series last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why iPhone Audio support in Apps is poor</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/01/why-iphone-audio-support-in-apps-is-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 22:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/01/why-iphone-audio-support-in-apps-is-poor/</guid>
      <description>3x 2″ binders full of documents. Looks like I have some reading to do.
PS: Happy new year. 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles nominated for Best Casual Game</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/31/smiles-nominated-for-best-casual-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 17:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/31/smiles-nominated-for-best-casual-game/</guid>
      <description>As the title says, Smiles is a finalist for Best Casual Game of 2008 on BestAppEver.com.
Visit this link and give it a vote.
http://bestappever.com/v/gcas
Thanks! 😀
And a reminder, Smiles Drop is on sale for $1.99 (reg $2.99) until the end of the day new years.
http://www.newyearappblowout.com
EDIT: The Smiles Drop sale is extended until Sunday the 4th. Sunday night though, it’s going back up.
Whee. 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physics in Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/physics-in-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 21:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/physics-in-smiles/</guid>
      <description>At first glance you wouldn’t think a matching game like Smiles would feature physics, but it does. In several places actually.
The most obvious example is the particle effects.
Particles were used when ice and rocks break, and also for the tile clearing effect. The tile would be erased instantly from the board, and a particle would be created in it’s place. The particle would zoom in, slow down, then zoom out with a twist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amusing bugs/oddities developing Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/amusing-bugsoddities-developing-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 19:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/amusing-bugsoddities-developing-smiles/</guid>
      <description>I kept video of some of my more interesting bugs/glitches/oddities in Smiles. Some more silly than others.
The first I want to show is a bug in one of the effects for the game mode Zen. It was supposed to be a “toss a rock in to a pond” water ripple. It didn’t really work as expected.
http://www.viddler.com/explore/PoVRAZOR/videos/8/
Here’s what it was supposed to look like. Cool looking, but the problem with this was the effect would make you queasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Drop New Years Sale, More</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/smiles-drop-new-years-sale-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 01:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/30/smiles-drop-new-years-sale-more/</guid>
      <description>Rather spontaneously, I decided to put Smiles Drop on sale for New Years.
So for a limited time (i.e. some time early Jan 2nd morning) you can grab Smiles Drop for the extremely reasonable price of $1.99 (save $1). That puts it in check, so you can buy Smiles Zen after that, and have paid the same price as buying full on Smiles. Well… you might save a penny buying separately, but still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smile Zen and Drop Available, News</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 02:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</guid>
      <description>It’s been 2 weeks, and much has happened.
As the topic suggests, Smiles Drop and Smiles Zen are now both available. $2.99 each, or save $1 by getting Smiles ($4.99).
So yeah, in a way that means I technically have 3 games out. As for blog content, I’m half way through a post on what went in to creating the video. Actually I was half through the Friday of the last post, but got caught up in the fact that I could actually take it easy for a couple days… and I sorta haven’t gone back to finish the post yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, a weekend</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/21/finally-a-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 23:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/21/finally-a-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I just finished up the other half of the game split a couple hours ago, “Smiles Drop”. It needs some testing first, but it should be off to Apple early/mid next week.
So here we are. Just over 3 weeks after finishing Smiles. Finished a video, finished a web site, finished a press release, finished contacting the websites, and now finished my releases for the next couple weeks.
Wow… I think I can finally take a weekend off now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen submitted to Apple</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 22:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>Part one of my rebellion against the iPhone price drop madness has begun. Smiles Zen, the standalone version of Zen is now sent to Apple.
If everything goes according to plan, it will be released bright and early Tuesday morning. This time, I explicitly set the date.
– – – – – – –
In other news, a new review.
http://osxreality.com/…/a-relaxing-matching-game-with-fun-graphics/
OSX Reality – 4 Stars. Incredibly favorable review. Their only beef was that they expect a price drop for it to be competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Website Update</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/16/smiles-website-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 01:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/16/smiles-website-update/</guid>
      <description>One thing lead to another, and I updated the Smiles website. It now has a fancy header, and a bit of a hint at what I’ll be up to in the coming weeks.
http://www.smiles-game.com
It also seems my press release/pack was picked up by 1up.
http://www.1up.com/do/gameOverview?cId=3169760
And that’s it for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Marketing Week</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/14/smiles-marketing-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 18:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/14/smiles-marketing-week/</guid>
      <description>And that about wraps up marketing week.
After finishing and finally getting the video uploaded Sunday night, Monday began my marketing blitz.
The day started well, with the almighty Tim taking the first initiative and sharing the video.
http://www.indiegames.com/blog/…
The rest of the Think Services network picked up on the FingerGaming review as part of the usual syndication.
Game Set Watch | GamaSutra
And continuing with Think Services, I entered the game in the IGF Mobile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sykhronics grins on to iPhone with Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/12/sykhronics-grins-on-to-iphone-with-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 12:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/12/sykhronics-grins-on-to-iphone-with-smiles/</guid>
      <description>London, Ontario, Canada – November 12th, 2008
Sykhronics Entertainment would like to introduce, Smiles. A brand new game now available for iPhone and iPod touch.
Smiles is a collection of 2 great games.
Smiles Drop is an unconventional action puzzle game. Unlike many others, you don’t have to wait to make your next move. In addition, you’re not pressured in to making that move either. Play at your own pace. Make matches, break ice and rocks, twisting and turning your way to higher scores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Smiles &amp;#8220;Hands on&amp;#8221; Video</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/10/final-smiles-hands-on-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/10/final-smiles-hands-on-video/</guid>
      <description>Final version of the Smiles video. It’s the short one again, but with me talking.
Here’s your chance to hear and mock Mike. I’ve been getting a number of positive and amusing comments from the video. Such fun things as that I sound like an Infomercial host, and music sounds like “corporate training music”. Finishing this video has been an incredible hassle. Hard drives dying, frequent reboots, loss of WAV file playback in Windows, and YouTube difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles &amp;#8220;5 Stars&amp;#8221; on Finger Gaming</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/04/smiles-5-stars-on-finger-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 16:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/04/smiles-5-stars-on-finger-gaming/</guid>
      <description>So I’m still working diligently to assemble my complete press package. Putting the final touches on that video, writing the press release, e-mails, all that fun stuff.
But as part of my procrastination routine, I’m hitting my usual list of sites. IndieGames, “The Sauce”, etc. And as I get to the iPhone gaming sites, I’m hit with this euphoric stupor.
“Dude! That’s me!”
“Duuuude! All them stars be yellow!”
http://fingergaming.com/2008/11/smiles/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles &amp;#8220;hands on&amp;#8221; video now available</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/03/smiles-hands-on-video-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 02:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/03/smiles-hands-on-video-now-available/</guid>
      <description>One of two promotional videos I’m making. This one is the “hands on” one, requiring a silly looking “camera on tripod hugging thing” to collect all the footage.
Viddler Long Version: http://www.viddler.com/…/19/
Youtube Short Version: http://www.youtube.com/E4sUK241aRA
Youtube Long Version: http://www.youtube.com/nEO1-zybCU4
In this video, I’m unfortunately assuming the player will pick up on all the nice things why this isn’t a Bejeweled clone. But to be sure, I’m going to spell it out next video, and briefly mention some of things not covered here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles &amp;#8220;Press Pack&amp;#8221; now online</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-press-pack-now-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 20:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-press-pack-now-online/</guid>
      <description>A press pack is now available for Smiles. Hit the website, it’s currently linked from the front page. Refresh if you don’t see it.
http://www.smiles-game.com
Screen shots and high-res logo and promo artwork.
Video is in progress. Hopefully by the end of the day Friday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles is Gold</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-is-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-is-gold/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from the grocery store, and got the word. “Ready for Sale“.
http://appshopper.com/games/smiles
Search for “Smiles” and scroll down a bit, or browse the puzzle or strategy categories in iTunes.
Contrary to the description, it’s an Action Puzzler. Lumines/Metoes ‘esc, or Bejeweled on crack.
Thanks to some fancy design kung fu, it’s also what the description says. But that’s a topic all in itself.
– – – –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;#8220;Smiles&amp;#8221; sent to Apple</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/28/smiles-sent-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 07:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/28/smiles-sent-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>I’d love to say the wait is over, but now we start the next wait. Waiting for approval.
As of 7:45 AM this Tuesday October 28th morning, the game is now sent.
– – – – – – –
Digging through my SVN logs for some stats.
Repository was created on June 22nd, 2008. That’s a total of 4 months and 6 days.
All code, art (except the original TTF font, though I did design and make the logo text), and audio created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love the TRC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/26/i-love-the-trc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 06:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/26/i-love-the-trc/</guid>
      <description>Wow, it’s been so long.
The last game I did TRC for was Atomic Betty, the Gameboy Advance game I worked on before leaving Big Blue Bubble. That would have been some time during July of 2005. That finished up, and I was a free man for August 1st.
By TRC I mean Technical Requirements Checklist. Every platform holder has them, though they sometimes have a different name for them. A TRC is a combination of guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 04:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s late, now 5 AM Saturday morning. Release Candidate 1 is just a few hours away. Some achievement tweaks, and minor bugs and we’re good.
Should go out to Apple on Monday afternoon. Then probably a week and it’ll be live in the App Store.
I’d have taken a photo, but I’m currently cameraless.
– – – –
The dummy website for the game:
http://www.smiles-game.com
Some time after it goes out, I’ll make a proper site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now leaving Bumpy Terrain Ville</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/09/21/now-leaving-bumpy-terrain-ville/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2008 18:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/09/21/now-leaving-bumpy-terrain-ville/</guid>
      <description>Still going…
Might actually be at a week +/- a couple days now. That stuff above was important, and means the rest should be easy. Of course, *should* is a funny word.
… and by +/-, I really mean +. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Close</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/24/getting-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 19:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/24/getting-close/</guid>
      <description>Still doin’ the perpetual “one more week”, but I’m close. Very close. If things go according to plan, we’ll be beta next Monday (September 1st). I want to sit on it a couple days and test the crap out of it, just to be sure it’s all good. Then off to Apple by Wednesday-Friday.
I wanted the promo+box art done a couple weeks ago, but I amusingly keep pushing it back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Something Insigtful</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/17/say-something-insigtful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 02:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/17/say-something-insigtful/</guid>
      <description>Yikes, it’s a weekend again already! Sunday too! Ack!
Rule of thumb. When Mike says game will be out in a week or two, assume month. Then assume longer.
Ahem.
There’s always the chance that this mysterious iPhone game may destroy my ‘cred’ as a physics guy. Though, I’ve been doing some fun stuff in it to rectify that.
I’ve found several uses for effects based on verlet and spring physics, even though the game lives in a world of tiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cruel tease</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/02/a-cruel-tease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2008 11:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/08/02/a-cruel-tease/</guid>
      <description>I must really enjoy being vague.
Three reasons for this. #1, I’m an ass. #2, The art is going through a major (final) overhaul at the moment. #3, I kinda don’t want my loyal viewer to pre-judge the game yet.
So the obvious answer, yes, it’s an iPhone game. Analysis of the mosaic well tell you a few things about the game, but to my credit, it’s not a clone. It’s a few things, but not a clone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All aboard the Hype Train!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/07/26/all-aboard-the-hype-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 09:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/07/26/all-aboard-the-hype-train/</guid>
      <description>August 1st, 2005. Three years ago this Friday. I was a burned out coder that left behind his jobs as Programmer, Senior and Lead Programmer, and eventually Technical Director at various game companies. A dozen handheld, mobile, and console titles to my name. A lifetime of game fascination and experience.
Next, I was starting my own.
Now, I’m not the only one of my former co-workers to do this, and certainly not the only one, but I didn’t want to do it the same as we’ve done before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>