<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scribbles on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/scribbles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scribbles on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 23:18:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/scribbles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales of a Silent H</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/14/tales-of-a-silent-h/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 23:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/14/tales-of-a-silent-h/</guid>
      <description>For whatever reason, I was inspired to start playing with logo designs. There&amp;rsquo;s no new decisions to be seen here in this post, just some ideas I&amp;rsquo;m playing with (and rejecting).
I actually used to make my own typography and font designs, one such example is this:
You can see more examples of prior logos here.
For the past 5 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this:
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really liked it, but it was good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Mushrooms and Logo Tests</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</guid>
      <description>Been caught up with a number of things. Here&amp;rsquo;s one I&amp;rsquo;m rather proud of, an animated Smiles mushroom animation.
Click for 400k animated gif
Animated in ToonBoom Studio.
Something else, an updated Sykhronics Logo animation.
That one is me goofing off in Sony Vegas.
Fun fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Difficulties (not really)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/11/27/technical-difficulties-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 02:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/11/27/technical-difficulties-not-really/</guid>
      <description>I hate “I&amp;rsquo;m still here” posts, but I still feel I owe something. Blame thinking too much, and being busy. I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan B</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/04/plan-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 01:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/04/plan-b/</guid>
      <description>Bleah. Waiting sucks.
On a completely unrelated note, some doodles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round 2</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/14/round-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2007 01:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/14/round-2/</guid>
      <description>Delay OK. More goods.
And a fish for good measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 minutes later</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/17/10-minutes-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2007 22:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/17/10-minutes-later/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketches and Website 2007</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/06/sketches-and-website-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 12:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/06/sketches-and-website-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m actively preparing for &amp;hellip; some event. On my to-do list for this miraculous day, is cleaning up the web sites. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finished 1 so far, the Sykhronics web site.
www.sykhronics.com
It&amp;rsquo;s not functional, but I think it looks cooler/more professional than before. I&amp;rsquo;ll make it usable at some later date.
Since it&amp;rsquo;s a new month, here&amp;rsquo;s a couple notable images from last month. The first is are a little sketch I did for each of my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s in their Christmas cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Dump, November 2006</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/12/01/sketch-dump-november-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/12/01/sketch-dump-november-2006/</guid>
      <description>Had a harder time this month scrounging up content unrelated to PuffBOMB I liked.
To be an ass, and to make everybody (else) behind the scenes happy, I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on this stuff until we&amp;rsquo;ve pitch it (Mid January is our target). Lots of tweaking and tuning, especially in the art style area. Getting a background look I&amp;rsquo;m happy with has turned out to be more troublesome than I&amp;rsquo;d hoped. None the less, the battle rages on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch Dump, October 2006</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/10/31/sketch-dump-october-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 09:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/10/31/sketch-dump-october-2006/</guid>
      <description>Just a few noteworthly doodles from my digital sketchbook. The scanner is too much work. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too much to say, so I drew a picture</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/26/too-much-to-say-so-i-drew-a-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2006 05:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/26/too-much-to-say-so-i-drew-a-picture/</guid>
      <description>When you haven&amp;rsquo;t updated in a long time, and you have a lot to say, where do you start?
Apparently you don&amp;rsquo;t say anything, and you put it off. Or you invent some random topic and post, but that&amp;rsquo;s only when you&amp;rsquo;re in a weird mood. OK, some friends inspired me to draw a picture, so lets talk art. Art, and what I&amp;rsquo;ve been investigating for a 2D art pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuffBOMB Concept Art 2003-2004</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/puffbomb-concept-art-2003-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 12:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/puffbomb-concept-art-2003-2004/</guid>
      <description>Due to the request of a compilation Classic PuffBOMB will be a part of, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected various bits of concept art and sketches from 2003 and 2004. Given that the game was a solo effort, and completely dependent on my art skill, it&amp;rsquo;s no “Art of Warcraft 3″ style giant happy book of fantastic reference doodles. No sir. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s just 4 collections of “learner artist” scribbles depicting some sort of character evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And there goes the 1st</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/02/and-there-goes-the-1st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2006 03:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/02/and-there-goes-the-1st/</guid>
      <description>So, that&amp;rsquo;s what happens on the 91&amp;rsquo;st day of the year shows up, your name is Mike, and you want to poke fun at casual gaming. You end up with a human body themed match 3, and an outrageous story that I don&amp;rsquo;t even want to rationalize. And yes, all Mike&amp;rsquo;s were thinking the exact same thing.
Yeah, this post is a rather plain one. Just a confirmation that yes, that was a joke, and an excuse to do an image dump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ritual Sacrifice</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/28/ritual-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/28/ritual-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>Page 50. Two and a half months later.
Sure it&amp;rsquo;s not front page news (except maybe for here), but it&amp;rsquo;s a small achievement I like to indulge myself in. Being a coder, I code a lot. Or at least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing professionally these past 6 years. So, I&amp;rsquo;m on a mission to improve my art and music skillzorz whilst on my adventures in independent game development. This little burning through a sketchbook challenge has been a constructive one for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project Finale, Part 7</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-finale-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 23:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-finale-part-7/</guid>
      <description>Low fat disposable hats present, part 7:
A Sunset in Stone Which is probably quite warm, despite the cold imagery of anything in stone&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; Why are you looking at me like that? Okay, I wanted an epic name to finish my cheesy little series of updates. Then it&amp;rsquo;s actual updates when they happen!!! Wow! That actually makes this a blog, instead of story time!
But I like story time &amp;hellip; So back to the technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 6</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 01:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Cream soda kung fu presents, part 6:
The Epic Tales of Hypocrisyism Viewer discretion is advised. So, right now, the current evolution of the character is this said goo blob thing. It shoots these tentacles/appendages out and swings, like any good monkey should.
However, for as long as I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about going with a gooey character, I&amp;rsquo;d been concerned about the Gishness factor. This “factor” is what I&amp;rsquo;m calling all the references to Gish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round and Up February</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/21/round-and-up-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 11:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/21/round-and-up-february/</guid>
      <description>Dude! There&amp;rsquo;s like, this site. And it has something to do with tunnels, or tunneling. Boy, I could tell you stories of tunneling. But they&amp;rsquo;re so amazing, they&amp;rsquo;d blow the minds of my 5 readers. The problem is I&amp;rsquo;d then have to acquire a new reader base. I can&amp;rsquo;t have that.
Right, so the more temporally correct but logically wrong February Round Up is online. Can you believe it? People mistakening the round up&amp;rsquo;s as horribly late or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 5</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 06:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Hey there sports fans. Our epic saga continues with part 5:
The Character (or I&amp;rsquo;m a little tea pot why are you reading this sub heading like I have something insightful to say e-i-e-i-o) Last we left our hero, he was an eight legged insect. Now he&amp;rsquo;s an eight legged insect looking for a job!!!
Now, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, he&amp;rsquo;s not a bad guy. You see, it&amp;rsquo;s not you, it&amp;rsquo;s me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-4/</guid>
      <description>So we have a character, and certain way the physics work. Cool. I want this game out reasonably soon, so that meant I needed to keep things simple. So minimal amounts of non functional stuff and no heavy animation. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an art team, just me. So the thought was to make the legs dangle and have shots of webbing shoot out.
And sure, this&amp;rsquo;ll make some nice still shots, but the character was going to be very nonfunctional looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-3/</guid>
      <description>And the legend continues.
Now, a spider would make a rather cool game character. Especially in a game about swinging. So I toyed with some designs, keeping in mind a sphere&amp;rsquo;ish geometric character, as shown in the collision diagram above. The following are some results of that early concept work.
And a new one for good measure.
But despite the abundance of designs, I was running into a sort of dilemma coming up with some easy ways to make the character functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Sykoland</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/welcome-to-sykoland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 00:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/welcome-to-sykoland/</guid>
      <description>And here we are. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s the start of a more regular practice. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably read the brief Manifesto to the right. This was written some 9 months ago. And now, since things are a tad more orderly, it&amp;rsquo;s time to expand on that.
Sykhronics, pronounced “psi-cron-icks”. A branding of Mike Kasprzak&amp;rsquo;s independent game works. Established in 1998, replacing my older branding Gamma Flare Games. After bouncing around the gracious hosting of a few friends, I acquired the “dot com” in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alright chums, lets do this...</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/01/alright-chums-lets-do-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 22:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/01/alright-chums-lets-do-this/</guid>
      <description>February the 1st. I&amp;rsquo;m mere minutes away from missing this chance to post and make the first of this month, yet I prevail. Ha ha!
Hopefully, I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting my act together. We&amp;rsquo;re already a month in to 2006, and really I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much to show. It seems I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a less than ideal situation up until recently. It&amp;rsquo;s resolution was equally as not so idealistic, so excuse me as I be vague, until the day we all look back and laugh about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamming from far away</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2006 00:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</guid>
      <description>Slamdance was last week. PuffBOMB was a finalist for the PopCap award. A game by the name of Odyssey took the award. Congratz to them. The rest of the results can be found here.
It&amp;rsquo;s a shame, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it out this year. That, and I&amp;rsquo;m still getting things off the ground here at Syko. I had heard from my “contact” there would be some PuffBOMB action at the festival, but so far my search for evidence has come up short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The year is new, and 3 weeks old</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/21/the-year-is-new-and-3-weeks-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2006 21:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/21/the-year-is-new-and-3-weeks-old/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it is certainly a newer year than before, and yet, I&amp;rsquo;m 3 weeks behind in declaring it as such. Ahh, this whole time thing you corporeal types take for granola.
I&amp;rsquo;m busy getting things in order on this side of screen. Big year, lots to do. Many sites that need work, and a game development crunch to kick off soon. Stay tuned. Check back every minute. ‘cmon, show my host how much you love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The monkey that spits robots</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve brought with me this horribly bright colored monster to burn your cornea. Hurah!
Right. Things are back and working in the Mike camp. Back to the grind and all. I&amp;rsquo;ve also recently finished a drawing pad, after slightly over 3 months. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like much, but looking back it&amp;rsquo;s been taking me up to a year to fill one up.
So IGF finalists have been announced. Funky. So many great games have been coming out later in the year, I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised PuffBOMB didn&amp;rsquo;t place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logo Rhythm</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/logo-rhythm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 21:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/logo-rhythm/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot going on, which I&amp;rsquo;ll go in to in further posts. This one&amp;rsquo;s on Logos.
Way back in July I dropped a note about some Rejected Logos. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t decided what I want, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been back playing the logo making game.
Ahh yes, a smooth graphic design&amp;rsquo;ish logo. Hurah.
Do I like it? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I&amp;rsquo;m torn between going with something more cartoony, or including a little face in the logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Life</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/17/plant-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 11:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/17/plant-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come up with a 3rd character to go along with the hamster and the robot for PuffBOMB. When I started redesigning the game, I wanted at least a male and a female character, but ended up with 2 males (3 if you count a butch hamster that I&amp;rsquo;d recently replaced with the robot).
It seems I have something. What you see to the right is a concept for the potted plant girl character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and Neglect</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/13/fear-and-neglect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2005 04:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/13/fear-and-neglect/</guid>
      <description>Oh don&amp;rsquo;t be scared baby, I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Yes, it seems I&amp;rsquo;ve been neglecting posting. On the plus side, there&amp;rsquo;s been some major progress, but equally major distractions. Since apparently leaving a job clearly means “2 month vacation”, there I was back at Big Blue for a week. All was good though. I was asked to help a struggling project meet a milestone, and that seemed to go well. Twas also nice to hang out with the guys there again, a fine group I must say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spread the Disease</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/25/spread-the-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/25/spread-the-disease/</guid>
      <description>Err&amp;hellip; maybe that&amp;rsquo;s not the most appropriate post title.
Yes, spreading is what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. Since I&amp;rsquo;m a nice guy, and since it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bad idea to wait, I&amp;rsquo;ve released the supped up classic 2003 PuffBOMB Prototype to the public. A download link can be found at the ‘official&amp;rsquo; PuffBOMB homepage, PuffBOMB.com.
Currently it&amp;rsquo;s only available for Windows. Hopefully, I can have the MacOS X version ready to go soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balloon Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/balloon-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 15:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/balloon-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Alright, this was inspired from a game idea I had a few years ago. In the midst of working on my new physics engine, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to revisit the idea and noticed an oddity in my design. Balloons.
Balloons are interesting. Unlike most objects in a game situation, they have this odd property of opposing gravity and going up. With that alone, we can do a convincing simulation in a game by consistently giving it an upward force larger than gravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGF and PuffBOMB clones?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 12:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</guid>
      <description>Well, well. The IGF 2006 Entries are now online, and we have a PuffBOMB clone to duel with. Impulse. It appers to be, according to the description, pretty much the same idea. Lets quote.
 Impulse: The player must place bombs and adjust their timers to make a ball hit the goal field. Obstacles, special elements and force fields provide varied levels. An interactive timeline helps controlling the game by jumping to specific times and guarantees a flexible and unique gameplay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready as ever</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/20/ready-as-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 20:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/20/ready-as-ever/</guid>
      <description>Hurah! Finally open. Welcome. Come on in and hear me think.
At some point throughout the day I was working. Really, I was; You can trust me. My new (3rd) office whiteboard just arrived this morning. I took the liberty of violating it with some math/physics filth. It seems to be holding up well, which is good, as I expect many more shamefull acts of mathematics to be performed on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blam!  Teaser</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 10:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</guid>
      <description>So begins the campaign. PuffBOMB.com/.net/.org are now online with this wonderful tease site. I&amp;rsquo;ll have banners show up in the indie world soon, just to build some awareness. I have some big plans for this game.
IGF polishing goes well. Just a few more graphics, and some minor updates to the game itself, and we&amp;rsquo;re good to go.
2 days left. We&amp;rsquo;re looking good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected Logos</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/01/rejected-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 03:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/01/rejected-logos/</guid>
      <description>On a mission to build corporate identity, the trials and tribulations of logo design. Given that introduction, &amp;hellip; yeah, I was playing with logo design ideas. At the end of the day, I didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly come up with something to use. None the less, this is my blog, and I feel compelled to share it with myself, and any other misguided net travelers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s “Ghastly logo“. For my own amusement, you can see it&amp;rsquo;s evolution below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignorant First Scribbles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/05/03/ignorant-first-scribbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2005 01:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/05/03/ignorant-first-scribbles/</guid>
      <description>Not much to say. I discovered an interesting feature I&amp;rsquo;m sure I knew, but always ignored in Paint Shop Pro. The wonderful world of layer masks. From an existing sketch we extract the line art as a mask, and can now do all kinds of fun coloring. We can fill in a whole layer with a color, apply the mask to only show color where the line art was, then color under on other layers to fill it in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>