<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PuffBOMB on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/puffbomb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PuffBOMB on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:05:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/puffbomb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Indie Indie Conversation</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! I figured now was a good time to talk about a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with for the past couple months now. Something we like to call, the Indie Indie Conversation. The conversation is a YouTube channel shared amongst a group of indie game developers where we talk about what we do, the challenges, and the lifestyle of creating games independently for a living.
I&amp;rsquo;ve personally failed many attempts at starting a regular video log here on my blog, and in retrospect that may have been the uncomfortable feeling of “talking to a wall”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuffBOMB Featured on GameJolt</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/puffbomb-featured-on-gamejolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 21:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/puffbomb-featured-on-gamejolt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m actually in the middle of a rather large post, but I still felt this was worth noting (while inappropriate for the other post). PuffBOMB, my explosive little freeware game is currently featured on GameJolt.
GameJolt is a unique games website that&amp;rsquo;s a bit like a “Kongregate” for freeware. I put PuffBOMB up there some time last week to try it out, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool.
The site has a neat feature for downloading and playing PC games right from the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 04:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s late, now 5 AM Saturday morning. Release Candidate 1 is just a few hours away. Some achievement tweaks, and minor bugs and we&amp;rsquo;re good.
Should go out to Apple on Monday afternoon. Then probably a week and it&amp;rsquo;ll be live in the App Store.
I&amp;rsquo;d have taken a photo, but I&amp;rsquo;m currently cameraless.
– – – –
The dummy website for the game:
http://www.smiles-game.com
Some time after it goes out, I&amp;rsquo;ll make a proper site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engines, Names and Evolution: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/04/engines-names-and-evolution-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 03:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/04/engines-names-and-evolution-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Ballistic Force wasn&amp;rsquo;t a long project, but development was dense.
Early on, I attempted a poorly conceived idea of creating densely constructed particle landscape. I wanted a system sort of like molecular/planetary attraction to keep scenery together, and allow clumping like a cartoon snowball rolling down a hill. It might have worked on something highly parallel like a GPU or the PS3&amp;rsquo;s SPE&amp;rsquo;s, but my design really wasn&amp;rsquo;t well thought out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engines, Names and Evolution: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/04/engines-names-and-evolution-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 02:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/04/engines-names-and-evolution-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This next engines name and story is a little complicated.
Game development became a constant burn out for me. Since finishing Secret Agent Barbie (Gameboy Advance) and Polly Pocket (Gameboy Advance), it became clear to me the only thing keeping me going was my fascination with new platforms. Certainly not the subject matter.
After we finished Polly Pocket, I asked for a month off to deal with my burn out. However, we quickly picked up a new game, Barbie: Gotta Have Games (Playstation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engines, Names and Evolution: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/01/engines-names-and-evolution-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 15:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/03/01/engines-names-and-evolution-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve given names to game engines I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. Most of my professional experience has been working on platformers and mini-game collections. Mini-games rarely share much in common, so by engines I&amp;rsquo;m referring to platformers, or engines for games very much like platformers.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to start talking about what I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about whilst designing my next engine. I need to set some context though, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through some of more significant engines I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/12/10/retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 07:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/12/10/retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, sorry. I wanted to do detailed commentary of The Spider stuffs, the in between stuff, and get in to the new PuffBOMB stuff, but it looks like it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. I wrote an outline and drafted a couple parts, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy with the results.
“New PuffBOMB” has been down to just me since October. The artist finished his work, which turned out great. Richard got a job, and has been unavailable to help since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Project, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/09/08/the-new-project-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2007 05:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/09/08/the-new-project-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Before starting work on “The Spider”, I was building the engine for the “new PuffBOMB”. The concept behind the engine, 2D characters and physics, 3D backgrounds styled to look 2D, HD ready. Pretty standard stuff.
The concept behind “The Spider” is, unlike a normal platformer where you stand on the ground, this one you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. Instead you would hang from and move along ceilings. The best idea I had at the time for pulling it off was something I nicknamed “double ropes”, one to support, and one for action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Project, Part 0</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/09/05/the-new-project-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 18:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/09/05/the-new-project-part-0/</guid>
      <description>Pestering works. So it&amp;rsquo;s September now. Last time I gave a *real* update was a year and a half ago. A 7+1 part blog series titled “And the Project”, where I introduced what went in to a concept I called “The Spider”. You can read it here:
Part 1, Part 2, Part 3, Part 4
Part 5, Part 6, Part 7, Part “+1″
Well, nearly a year and a half later, as expected a lot has happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitch Video Trailer Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/02/19/pitch-video-trailer-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 22:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/02/19/pitch-video-trailer-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>I was busy last month cutting together a trailer for&amp;hellip; business purposes. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about this later. It turned out surprisingly more difficult that I had have hoped, but I found a rather unique way of pulling it together.
Obviously, the secret weapon is Fraps. Trying to nab constant 60fps footage was doable, but proved tricky, due to my hard drives not being the most defragged. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many takes later, I ended up with nearly an hour of game footage, that was cut down to a 4 minute presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Illustrator or Animator needed</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/30/2d-illustrator-or-animator-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 18:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/30/2d-illustrator-or-animator-needed/</guid>
      <description>This posting has been filled. Thanks everyone.
– – – –
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little job posting that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to circulate.
[edit] Edited, &amp;lsquo;cause it was rather technical and mean sounding. – – – –
Hi there,
We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a skilled 2D illustrator or animator for a 2 month contract, to start some time in February. The work can be done remotely. This is a full time contract, and I expect it to be on par with industry wages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh right, a compilation too</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 10:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</guid>
      <description>It seems I missed the memo.
The 2nd Independent Games compilation was released back in September (25th), and that PuffBOMB game I seem to talk about all the time was included.
As well, there was a set of concept art included in the package. Said art can also be seen right here.
I suppose I should go find a way to acquire a copy, &amp;lsquo;cause I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what happened to a complimentary one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuffBOMB Concept Art 2003-2004</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/puffbomb-concept-art-2003-2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 12:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/puffbomb-concept-art-2003-2004/</guid>
      <description>Due to the request of a compilation Classic PuffBOMB will be a part of, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected various bits of concept art and sketches from 2003 and 2004. Given that the game was a solo effort, and completely dependent on my art skill, it&amp;rsquo;s no “Art of Warcraft 3″ style giant happy book of fantastic reference doodles. No sir. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s just 4 collections of “learner artist” scribbles depicting some sort of character evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June, can&#39;t forget June</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/06/23/june-cant-forget-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 20:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/06/23/june-cant-forget-june/</guid>
      <description>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to let the month go by without posting something. After all, I have been doing much stuff. Not so much round up, but many many other things.
The project progresses. We&amp;rsquo;re busy preparing a pitch-able playable of the game that we&amp;rsquo;ll be pitchely pitching to potential pitch-able people pretty pitching soon. I&amp;rsquo;ll have less riddles and more to say about that in a few weeks.
Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve silently (and finally) put together a MacOS X version of PuffBOMB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Gamer UK 2006</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/10/pc-gamer-uk-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2006 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/10/pc-gamer-uk-2006/</guid>
      <description>In the mag and on the coverdisk of PC Gamer UK&amp;rsquo;s March 2006 issue. The Puffiest BOMB of them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project Finale, Part 7</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-finale-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 23:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-finale-part-7/</guid>
      <description>Low fat disposable hats present, part 7:
A Sunset in Stone Which is probably quite warm, despite the cold imagery of anything in stone&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; Why are you looking at me like that? Okay, I wanted an epic name to finish my cheesy little series of updates. Then it&amp;rsquo;s actual updates when they happen!!! Wow! That actually makes this a blog, instead of story time!
But I like story time &amp;hellip; So back to the technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 6</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2006 01:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/25/and-the-project-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Cream soda kung fu presents, part 6:
The Epic Tales of Hypocrisyism Viewer discretion is advised. So, right now, the current evolution of the character is this said goo blob thing. It shoots these tentacles/appendages out and swings, like any good monkey should.
However, for as long as I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about going with a gooey character, I&amp;rsquo;d been concerned about the Gishness factor. This “factor” is what I&amp;rsquo;m calling all the references to Gish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 5</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 06:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Hey there sports fans. Our epic saga continues with part 5:
The Character (or I&amp;rsquo;m a little tea pot why are you reading this sub heading like I have something insightful to say e-i-e-i-o) Last we left our hero, he was an eight legged insect. Now he&amp;rsquo;s an eight legged insect looking for a job!!!
Now, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, he&amp;rsquo;s not a bad guy. You see, it&amp;rsquo;s not you, it&amp;rsquo;s me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-4/</guid>
      <description>So we have a character, and certain way the physics work. Cool. I want this game out reasonably soon, so that meant I needed to keep things simple. So minimal amounts of non functional stuff and no heavy animation. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an art team, just me. So the thought was to make the legs dangle and have shots of webbing shoot out.
And sure, this&amp;rsquo;ll make some nice still shots, but the character was going to be very nonfunctional looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/07/and-the-project-part-3/</guid>
      <description>And the legend continues.
Now, a spider would make a rather cool game character. Especially in a game about swinging. So I toyed with some designs, keeping in mind a sphere&amp;rsquo;ish geometric character, as shown in the collision diagram above. The following are some results of that early concept work.
And a new one for good measure.
But despite the abundance of designs, I was running into a sort of dilemma coming up with some easy ways to make the character functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/05/and-the-project-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 15:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/05/and-the-project-part-2/</guid>
      <description>And now, part 2. This part I&amp;rsquo;ll call&amp;hellip;
Spiderphobia (versus the more correct Arachnophobia. Correctness is wrong) Spiders, spiders, and more spiders. So the game concept I decided to toy with is one I like to call “The Spider”. The concept itself is most similar to the rope platformer Umihara Kawase, a slick game a former employee introduced me to (thanks Gary). In indie land, the closest similar game to that would be Wik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the Project, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/05/and-the-project-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/05/and-the-project-part-1/</guid>
      <description>And now, what&amp;rsquo;s been going on.
As mentioned previously, things started out as my long overdue PuffBOMB remake. So, a physics engine was built, based on what I&amp;rsquo;d learned from various tech demo&amp;rsquo;s (which I&amp;rsquo;ll post at a later date). And it did cool stuff.
Good ‘ol verlet physics action. What you can see above is “characters” composed of spheres (circles), connected by springs. Cool stuff. The 3 circle thang is a potential collision model for the PuffBOMB hamster, and the Balloon like thing is exactly that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamming from far away</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2006 00:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</guid>
      <description>Slamdance was last week. PuffBOMB was a finalist for the PopCap award. A game by the name of Odyssey took the award. Congratz to them. The rest of the results can be found here.
It&amp;rsquo;s a shame, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it out this year. That, and I&amp;rsquo;m still getting things off the ground here at Syko. I had heard from my “contact” there would be some PuffBOMB action at the festival, but so far my search for evidence has come up short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamdance 2006 Casual Finalist</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 12:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</guid>
      <description>Not bad for a game originally created for a 48 hour competition. The 2006 PopCap Casual Game Award Finalists:  Cloud – Cloud Joboo’s Gems – Gem Jocks Ocular Ink – Pistachio Productions The Odyssey – Liquid Dragon Studios PuffBOMB – Sykhronics Entertainment  Press release can be found here.
In the unlikely circumstance that someone who&amp;rsquo;s actually attending reads my blog, I&amp;rsquo;d greatly appreciate any photos of the game at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bravo Screenfun 2003</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/bravo-screenfun-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/bravo-screenfun-2003/</guid>
      <description>Again, for my amusement. PuffBOMB in the German gaming magazine, Bravo Screenfun. December 2003 issue. The game was later republished on the October 2005 coverdisk, but didn&amp;rsquo;t make the screenshot page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Zone 2005</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/pc-zone-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/pc-zone-2005/</guid>
      <description>For my own amusement, PuffBOMB in UK PC gaming magazine PC Zone. January 2006 Issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The monkey that spits robots</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve brought with me this horribly bright colored monster to burn your cornea. Hurah!
Right. Things are back and working in the Mike camp. Back to the grind and all. I&amp;rsquo;ve also recently finished a drawing pad, after slightly over 3 months. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like much, but looking back it&amp;rsquo;s been taking me up to a year to fill one up.
So IGF finalists have been announced. Funky. So many great games have been coming out later in the year, I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised PuffBOMB didn&amp;rsquo;t place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiders</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/10/spiders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 06:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/10/spiders/</guid>
      <description>Yep, I died. No, wait.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy pulling a prototype together. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say just yet. I have a pretty ambitious goal to meet by the end of this month, and I&amp;rsquo;ll gladly talk about it then. I even brought on some help, as I think timing is crucial.
If this works out, we should see some PuffBOMB action in about a year.
I like consoles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plant Life</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/17/plant-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2005 11:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/17/plant-life/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come up with a 3rd character to go along with the hamster and the robot for PuffBOMB. When I started redesigning the game, I wanted at least a male and a female character, but ended up with 2 males (3 if you count a butch hamster that I&amp;rsquo;d recently replaced with the robot).
It seems I have something. What you see to the right is a concept for the potted plant girl character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and Neglect</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/13/fear-and-neglect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2005 04:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/13/fear-and-neglect/</guid>
      <description>Oh don&amp;rsquo;t be scared baby, I&amp;rsquo;m still here.
Yes, it seems I&amp;rsquo;ve been neglecting posting. On the plus side, there&amp;rsquo;s been some major progress, but equally major distractions. Since apparently leaving a job clearly means “2 month vacation”, there I was back at Big Blue for a week. All was good though. I was asked to help a struggling project meet a milestone, and that seemed to go well. Twas also nice to hang out with the guys there again, a fine group I must say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spread the Disease</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/25/spread-the-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 17:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/25/spread-the-disease/</guid>
      <description>Err&amp;hellip; maybe that&amp;rsquo;s not the most appropriate post title.
Yes, spreading is what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. Since I&amp;rsquo;m a nice guy, and since it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bad idea to wait, I&amp;rsquo;ve released the supped up classic 2003 PuffBOMB Prototype to the public. A download link can be found at the ‘official&amp;rsquo; PuffBOMB homepage, PuffBOMB.com.
Currently it&amp;rsquo;s only available for Windows. Hopefully, I can have the MacOS X version ready to go soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for August</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/tunnel-for-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 22:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/tunnel-for-august/</guid>
      <description>The round up is here. Hurah.
An underwater sequel to Cosmo Bots, a mech 3D shooter War World, Diablo meets Gauntlet in Evil Invasion, and a double dose of cavemen. An alright month. We&amp;rsquo;ve had better.
But wait! What is this? Bright red, black, orange and blue banners? Oh noes! What could this be? An add campaign for some wacky game? Inconceivable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGF and PuffBOMB clones?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 12:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</guid>
      <description>Well, well. The IGF 2006 Entries are now online, and we have a PuffBOMB clone to duel with. Impulse. It appers to be, according to the description, pretty much the same idea. Lets quote.
 Impulse: The player must place bombs and adjust their timers to make a ball hit the goal field. Obstacles, special elements and force fields provide varied levels. An interactive timeline helps controlling the game by jumping to specific times and guarantees a flexible and unique gameplay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s a Slamdance too?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/15/theres-a-slamdance-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 06:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/15/theres-a-slamdance-too/</guid>
      <description>Apparently I forgot about this. The Slamdance Guerrilla Gamemaker Competition is yet another IGF like compo. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s actually worth any prizes&amp;hellip; at least none their publicizing. Either way, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a publicity pack for them, and will be sending it off today. A shame that they&amp;rsquo;re making me pay to enter. Buh.
I think what turned me off about this “way back when” was that the game had to be profitless, but apparently that&amp;rsquo;s not the case anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check, we&#39;re in</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/07/check-were-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2005 01:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/07/check-were-in/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, it seems I misplaced this blog post.
With less than 5 hours to spare, it&amp;rsquo;s in. Excellent. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t without it&amp;rsquo;s drama though. Once confirmed by myself, my brother, and a few friends that everything was good, I began to upload. *OH GOOD*, the upload server was acting up! Ack!
Within 20 minutes things cleared up. I snuck my game into it&amp;rsquo;s folder, hit the switch, and waited as it&amp;rsquo;s bytes were sucked out of Canada into some server likely in the California area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T minus 10, 9, 8, ...</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/06/t-minus-10-9-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 01:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/06/t-minus-10-9-8/</guid>
      <description>Clock is ticking.
Yep. In one sense, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to go. I filled out the submission for yesterday, and paid my entry fee. Apparently however, you need an installer. *Oh*. So today, after finishing the missing graphics, I got to do that. Huge thanks to Seth for sharing with me his NSIS script, which saved me hours of digging for little things like uninstaller cleanlyness, icon changing, and so many silly little things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blam!  Teaser</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 10:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</guid>
      <description>So begins the campaign. PuffBOMB.com/.net/.org are now online with this wonderful tease site. I&amp;rsquo;ll have banners show up in the indie world soon, just to build some awareness. I have some big plans for this game.
IGF polishing goes well. Just a few more graphics, and some minor updates to the game itself, and we&amp;rsquo;re good to go.
2 days left. We&amp;rsquo;re looking good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrambled Eggs</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/03/scrambled-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2005 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/03/scrambled-eggs/</guid>
      <description>A bit of a last minute scramble to get something together for the IGF. My original idea of getting the new game up and running, hahahaha&amp;hellip; erm, sadly no. Progress is good, but not that good. However, I still am sending something. What I&amp;rsquo;m sending is the old PuffBOMB, from over 2 years ago, with a fresh paint job. The new look finally brings together my style ideas for the game from the past couple years It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to finally see it in action, and to know, does it suck or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>