<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>In The Media on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/in-the-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in In The Media on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 14:31:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/in-the-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One more prize for the road</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 14:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Progress on the tech for my upcoming game “Alone, The” has been a little slow the past couple weeks, due to Ludum Dare, a nightmare of server issues (both LD and my own), and my upcoming move (OMG THAT’S RIGHT NOW). I have some great news to share though:
 TransGaming Announces Winner of the $10,000 GameTree Developer Competition: Developer’s Choice Award Developers from around the world have their say: Smiles HD takes home the prize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nope, not this time</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</guid>
      <description>No sir. Do not pass go, do not collect $50,000.
However! All is not lost!
I am still eligible for a the $10k “Developers Choice” award, which means you, you developers! Visit GameTreeDeveloper.com and cast your vote (For Smiles HD). 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I might win something&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</guid>
      <description>The latest in the world of Mike, I might win something again.
I’m less than an hour away from finding out if it’s true, so here’s me killing minutes as I wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towlr at &amp;#8220;N Design&amp;#8221; Exhibit</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/21/towlr-at-n-design-exhibit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/07/21/towlr-at-n-design-exhibit/</guid>
      <description>Towlr recently frustrated attendees at “N Design”, an art-game exhibit in Curitiba, Brazil. Very cool!
Here are some photos of the event.
Several other favorites were at the event, included a Rohrer game, a Terry Cavanagh game, and of course, Braid.
More details can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Poster Boy</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/21/vnc-poster-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 09:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/05/21/vnc-poster-boy/</guid>
      <description>Heh, I certainly wasn’t expecting this.
RealVNC has a rotating twitter quotes on their front page, and it seems I’m now part of the rotation.
And yes, that is a real quote; I do think VNC is awesome. Admittedly, I’ve been using UltraVNC on my PC’s recently, though I do run their iPhone client. 😉
Thanks for the tip Adam.
– – –
I FINALLY submitted my Moblin (Linux) AppUp port of Smiles late last night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automobiles, Interviews, all Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 22:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</guid>
      <description>To say 2010 has been a busy year would be an understatement.
While we were all waiting for Apple to confirm the existence of the iPad, I was busy tweaking, improving, and porting my game Smiles to a bunch of new platforms. The most significant port by far was to Netbook PCs for Intel’s AppUp Center, a brand new App Store coming soon to Netbooks everywhere.
To say Intel and AppUp have been good to me, that would be another understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD &amp;#8211; Gameplay Videos!</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/29/smiles-hd-gameplay-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 23:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/29/smiles-hd-gameplay-videos/</guid>
      <description>Oh hey. Like literally an hour or two after that big epic blog post of mine, Apple let us know we could submit early. So I crunched the game together and did exactly that.
Here’s some final video footage of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike the Multi-Winner and GDC Champion</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</guid>
      <description>So, holy cow! GDC was absolutely insane! I almost don’t know where to start, but lets start from the beginning.
First thing first, I won again!!
Yes, as if winning a free car wasn’t enough, I also won a free trip to GDC. So Intel ended up covering my flight, putting me up in a fancy hotel, gave me some spending money, treating me to dinner, AND giving me nearly front row seats to a San Jose Sharks hockey game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike&amp;#8217;s GDC 2010 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/06/mikes-gdc-2010-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2010 07:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/06/mikes-gdc-2010-schedule/</guid>
      <description>For the benefit of friends and people I’m meeting at the show, here’s a run down of my itinerary for GDC. I’ll also be tweeting and watching twitter while I’m down for any impromptu meets, hang-outs, and whatever with people I know. If the twitter says “totally bored”, then you know. 🙂
If anybody I know needs my cell number, send me a quick e-mail (mike AT sykhronics dot com). It’s not my usual cell, but it’ll be my number whilst I’m in San Fran.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalizing your GDC pass</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 22:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</guid>
      <description>Ordinarily, greeting someone by glancing at their chest might be seen as a little rude (especially a lady), but at GDC it’s encouraged! Yes I’m talking about the passes, not making a pass.
The passes do a good job of helping you connect a face to a name, and even a company, but you don’t always know who made or represents what. GDC passes include a relatively large pocket, so you could either make something to insert behind your name card, or cover the pass with some strategically placed stickers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Different GDC (for me)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</guid>
      <description>So last year, I was an IGF Mobile finalist. This little game of mine stood alongside iPhone favorites like Edge and Fieldrunners, vying for the “Best Mobile Game” award. And if I had won, … well, I have no idea. Even just being a finalist has been great for me, so I’d image it would have been MORE great. 😉
That was 2009, and this is 2010.
This year started out as my “low key” and “quiet” GDC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &amp;#8220;Intel is awesome&amp;#8221; post</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/03/the-intel-is-awesome-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/03/the-intel-is-awesome-post/</guid>
      <description>So hey. Back in December I finished up a 1.0 port of Smiles for Netbooks, and sent it to Intel by their early contest deadline.
And hey, guess what?
Link here.
Second place! That’s awesome. 😀
So hey, what does 2nd place actually mean?
Wow. So I guess I’ve got a pretty good story now when mingling at GDC. 😀
I’ll post some photos once it arrives.
Woohoo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike&amp;#8217;s 2009</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 19:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</guid>
      <description>So wow. That’s finally it for 2009. Like doing taxes ever year, I feel a special sort of obligation that I write some sort of retrospective, especially after such an eventful year as this one. Far more awesome than taxes. 😉
I wasn’t sure where to start, so I ended up categorizing aspects of the year. I’ll free form rant about each topic as I come to it.
Let’s begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The book is real, and more</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/06/15/the-book-is-real-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 17:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/06/15/the-book-is-real-and-more/</guid>
      <description>First on the agenda, the book is real.

As you can see above, my three complimentary copies showed up in the mail today. Word from the Dread Pirate himself (i.e. Lead Author/Tech Reviewer) is the books should be en route, if not already arriving at book stores all over the place. After all, the guy in Canada got his. 😉
– – – – –
Next, a Smiles update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First, the other stuff</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/05/09/first-the-other-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 05:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/05/09/first-the-other-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Crawling out of bed early this morning, I made the weird decision that it’d be a blogging morning. It seems I’ve stockpiled a few interesting things to talk about. I’m nearly ready to start talking about the new project too, but as the title suggests, I’ll be talking about the other stuff today.
First thing on the agenda, Ludum Dare. I wanted to follow up that prior post of mine with a brief finale post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smile Zen and Drop Available, News</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 02:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</guid>
      <description>It’s been 2 weeks, and much has happened.
As the topic suggests, Smiles Drop and Smiles Zen are now both available. $2.99 each, or save $1 by getting Smiles ($4.99).
So yeah, in a way that means I technically have 3 games out. As for blog content, I’m half way through a post on what went in to creating the video. Actually I was half through the Friday of the last post, but got caught up in the fact that I could actually take it easy for a couple days… and I sorta haven’t gone back to finish the post yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen submitted to Apple</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 22:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>Part one of my rebellion against the iPhone price drop madness has begun. Smiles Zen, the standalone version of Zen is now sent to Apple.
If everything goes according to plan, it will be released bright and early Tuesday morning. This time, I explicitly set the date.
– – – – – – –
In other news, a new review.
http://osxreality.com/…/a-relaxing-matching-game-with-fun-graphics/
OSX Reality – 4 Stars. Incredibly favorable review. Their only beef was that they expect a price drop for it to be competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles &amp;#8220;5 Stars&amp;#8221; on Finger Gaming</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/04/smiles-5-stars-on-finger-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 16:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/04/smiles-5-stars-on-finger-gaming/</guid>
      <description>So I’m still working diligently to assemble my complete press package. Putting the final touches on that video, writing the press release, e-mails, all that fun stuff.
But as part of my procrastination routine, I’m hitting my usual list of sites. IndieGames, “The Sauce”, etc. And as I get to the iPhone gaming sites, I’m hit with this euphoric stupor.
“Dude! That’s me!”
“Duuuude! All them stars be yellow!”
http://fingergaming.com/2008/11/smiles/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh right, a compilation too</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 10:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</guid>
      <description>It seems I missed the memo.
The 2nd Independent Games compilation was released back in September (25th), and that PuffBOMB game I seem to talk about all the time was included.
As well, there was a set of concept art included in the package. Said art can also be seen right here.
I suppose I should go find a way to acquire a copy, ’cause I’m not sure what happened to a complimentary one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Gamer UK 2006</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/10/pc-gamer-uk-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2006 14:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/10/pc-gamer-uk-2006/</guid>
      <description>In the mag and on the coverdisk of PC Gamer UK’s March 2006 issue. The Puffiest BOMB of them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a future where dev is illegal</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/07/in-a-future-where-dev-is-illegal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 11:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/07/in-a-future-where-dev-is-illegal/</guid>
      <description>Ahh the Escapist. A fine weekly online publication.
I had the chance to contribute to an interesting conversation, about a world where developing games was illegal, and what you would do. Of course, it’s only appropriate I took the sarcastic “my life is ruined” angle. Allen from the Escapist approved, and posted this.
 Turn to drugs, live on the street and sell myself cheaply to get by.
  – Mike Kasprzak, sykhronics entertainment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamdance 2006 Casual Finalist</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 12:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</guid>
      <description>Not bad for a game originally created for a 48 hour competition. —
The 2006 PopCap Casual Game Award Finalists:
Cloud – Cloud
Joboo’s Gems – Gem Jocks
Ocular Ink – Pistachio Productions
The Odyssey – Liquid Dragon Studios
PuffBOMB – Sykhronics Entertainment
—
Press release can be found here.
In the unlikely circumstance that someone who’s actually attending reads my blog, I’d greatly appreciate any photos of the game at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bravo Screenfun 2003</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/bravo-screenfun-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/bravo-screenfun-2003/</guid>
      <description>Again, for my amusement. PuffBOMB in the German gaming magazine, Bravo Screenfun. December 2003 issue. The game was later republished on the October 2005 coverdisk, but didn’t make the screenshot page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Zone 2005</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/pc-zone-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 14:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/15/pc-zone-2005/</guid>
      <description>For my own amusement, PuffBOMB in UK PC gaming magazine PC Zone. January 2006 Issue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>