<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Business of Things on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/the-business-of-things/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Business of Things on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 01:44:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/the-business-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I am retiring from Indie Game Dev</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2015/06/29/i-am-retiring-from-indie-game-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 01:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2015/06/29/i-am-retiring-from-indie-game-dev/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s true. After 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;ll be wrapping up my games business. Later this year, I&amp;rsquo;ll be moving on to other things.
I am still going to be around. I&amp;rsquo;d still like to attend GDC in San Francisco every year. Ludum Dare is a thing I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to work on and run (and if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky, I might be able to enter again some day). I&amp;rsquo;m also going to continue doing little projects that amuse me, things like my Commodore 64 game from New Years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Modern Middlewares</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2013/04/22/evaluating-modern-middlewares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 01:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2013/04/22/evaluating-modern-middlewares/</guid>
      <description>The following is some rambling. I have a point I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make, but I&amp;rsquo;m certain I don&amp;rsquo;t make it. My fingers kept moving, and this is what resulted. You can kinda get an idea what sort of madness is bouncing around in the ‘ol noodle right now though. Good luck.
 *Big Sigh*
I&amp;rsquo;m typically a “from scratch”, “native code is best”, “c++ FTW” type of developer. The thing is, developers with my skillset and experience really are at a big disadvantage in today&amp;rsquo;s game market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New Cards</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2013/03/01/the-new-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 17:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2013/03/01/the-new-cards/</guid>
      <description>
Ordered from Morning Print. White plastic, thin, nice and vibrant, and practically indestructible!
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;amp;mdash; Mr The Mike Kasprzak (@mikekasprzak) &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/mikekasprzak/status/307608399229620224&amp;quot;&amp;gt;March 1, 2013&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rebranding of Sykhronics</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2013/02/27/the-rebranding-of-sykhronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 17:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2013/02/27/the-rebranding-of-sykhronics/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend I began a process of rebranding my company. Shortly after leaving my AAA job in 2005, I created this logo.

Thing is, that&amp;rsquo;s not even one of the better logos I used, it&amp;rsquo;s just the most business&amp;rsquo;y one.
More here.
As you can see, I used to be really in to playing with typography. Sykhronics is a name I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for the past 15 years. In the early days, it was my portfolio website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Because We May Sale</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://toonormal.com/assets/uploads/2012/05/Atwx4_gCIAAQ5Hq.jpg-larg2e.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becausewemay.com&#34;&gt;Because We May&lt;/a&gt;, a grandiose cross platform mega sale is on right now. Android, iPad, iPhone, PC (Desura), and Blackberry Playbook versions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smileshd.com&#34;&gt;Smiles and Smiles HD&lt;/a&gt; are all heavily discounted and available for about $2. The sale ends June 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinventing</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/11/10/reinventing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/11/10/reinventing/</guid>
      <description>Enough of this non-game talk.
The past month has been extremely good for progress. I did not meet my goal for the month, but I&amp;rsquo;d be silly to complain. Yadda yadda ya.
Against my better judgement, I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop beating around the bush and show you:
A mish-mash or random objects sitting in some sculpted terrain. Subtle glow. Vignette blur.
 That&amp;rsquo;s cool Mike, but what is it?
 Tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Synology NAS, two months later</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/10/29/the-synology-nas-two-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 20:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/10/29/the-synology-nas-two-months-later/</guid>
      <description>NAS time, again! Like before, I&amp;rsquo;m collecting my notes and thoughts all in one place.
Two months later Why have 1 when you can have 2? After winning the GameTree prize, I decided I should have 2
So according to my blog here, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running the Synology NAS for just over 2 months now, and I still love it. Heck, I bought a 2nd one! The NAS has become a permanent part of my development setup, and even my development workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One more prize for the road</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 14:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/09/01/one-more-prize-for-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Progress on the tech for my upcoming game “Alone, The” has been a little slow the past couple weeks, due to Ludum Dare, a nightmare of server issues (both LD and my own), and my upcoming move (OMG THAT&amp;rsquo;S RIGHT NOW). I have some great news to share though:
 TransGaming Announces Winner of the $10,000 GameTree Developer Competition: Developer&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award Developers from around the world have their say: Smiles HD takes home the prize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AppDailySales, and running on Synology NAS Devices</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/08/23/appdailysales-and-running-on-synology-nas-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 23:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/08/23/appdailysales-and-running-on-synology-nas-devices/</guid>
      <description>Continuing my prior post where I talk about my server replacement, a Synology NAS (DS211j). In essence, a cheap, tiny dedicated Linux box featuring an ARM CPU and custom web UI specially designed for SUPER EASY RAID array maintenance and creation. There&amp;rsquo;s a 4 drive version, some many-more drive versions, but they cost more.
This time, I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about a little tool for getting your daily sales data from Apple&amp;rsquo;s iTunes Connect website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am running a Synology NAS now</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/08/23/i-am-running-a-synology-nas-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 22:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/08/23/i-am-running-a-synology-nas-now/</guid>
      <description>Last week, a drive in my server died. These drives weren&amp;rsquo;t really that old, but were Seagate&amp;rsquo;s from the drive failing epidemic a few years back. I bought 6 drives around this time, 4 for the server in a RAID 10 array, 2 for my workstation. I lost 1 to the failure problem, and the rest I managed to get updated firmwares installed in time.
Since then, I have been extremely leery of Seagate drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nope, not this time</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 21:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/nope-not-this-time/</guid>
      <description>No sir. Do not pass go, do not collect $50,000.
  However! All is not lost!
I am still eligible for a the $10k “Developers Choice” award, which means you, you developers! Visit GameTreeDeveloper.com and cast your vote (For Smiles HD). 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I might win something...</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 18:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/i-might-win-something/</guid>
      <description>The latest in the world of Mike, I might win something again.
  I&amp;rsquo;m less than an hour away from finding out if it&amp;rsquo;s true, so here&amp;rsquo;s me killing minutes as I wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation: Business and Fear</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/conversation-business-and-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 01:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/conversation-business-and-fear/</guid>
      <description>From Monday, Gianfranco (whom I abbreviate as GB) was concerned that some of the guys might have been fear-mongering after a recent set of very sad sad videos. That catapulted me in to a rant about&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s actually that way. Indie truths a-plenty.
The first begins on the subject of “big games are extremely risky”, despite doing one myself right now.
  I had some upload issues with the prior video, which lead me to watching my video a few more times, and expanding on the subject of indies and failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Indie Indie Conversation</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! I figured now was a good time to talk about a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with for the past couple months now. Something we like to call, the Indie Indie Conversation. The conversation is a YouTube channel shared amongst a group of indie game developers where we talk about what we do, the challenges, and the lifestyle of creating games independently for a living.
I&amp;rsquo;ve personally failed many attempts at starting a regular video log here on my blog, and in retrospect that may have been the uncomfortable feeling of “talking to a wall”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/ending-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/ending-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Yes, you read that right. It is ending. For real.
June 23rd is the 3 year anniversary of Smiles (as in, starting the game). I have finished every single port of the game that I had planned on doing (except console ports, both I decided to abort); Some are still in submission or need of final packaging. Days away now.
Today is June 15th, a whole week away from the anniversary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So much for that</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/so-much-for-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/06/15/so-much-for-that/</guid>
      <description>Hey, well that didn&amp;rsquo;t work. Smiles for WP7 after a couple weeks.
Note, that&amp;rsquo;s cumulative&amp;hellip; which means total overall
Or according to my data: 9 trial downloads, and 1 sale since. There was some twitter talking, some retweets by fellow devs, but there&amp;rsquo;s practically no noticeable spike.
Ah well, so much for that. On to bigger better things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOS: Save our Smiles (for WP7)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/05/24/sos-save-our-smiles-for-wp7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 20:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/05/24/sos-save-our-smiles-for-wp7/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I just received a 2nd e-mail informing me my “Microsoft Windows Phone Marketplace developer account” yearly membership needs to be renewed. That costs $99 USD, and I think I paid $129 CAD.
I made this game (Smiles), and I paid a friend to work with me to port it to Windows Phone 7:
  It was available on launch day for Windows Phone 7. Looks like a pretty well made game, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five years as a full-time Indie</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/03/five-years-as-a-full-time-indie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 05:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/12/03/five-years-as-a-full-time-indie/</guid>
      <description>The exact timing is a little off, but I today just renewed my business license.
Yes, 5 years ago July I left my job as Technical Director at Big Blue Bubble (now one of Canada&amp;rsquo;s largest game studios &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;re welcome ;)). Here&amp;rsquo;s what I had to say.
 All systems are go!
July 29th, 2005 – 10:34 PM
Amazing. Today was my official last day at Big Blue Bubble. BBB was a great place to work, but I’m a too ambitious for my own good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eighty Five Percent</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/30/eighty-five-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 03:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/30/eighty-five-percent/</guid>
      <description>Alright, time to get back in to the routine.
It&amp;rsquo;s been two weeks since the last post. Last week became an impromptu holiday for me — I am a Canadian living in Canada, but I deal mostly with US companies, so American Thanksgiving seemed safe.
The week prior was busy though. I sent off the initial version of Smiles HD for the Mac App Store. It still sits in the approval queue, but I&amp;rsquo;m there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales of a Silent H</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/14/tales-of-a-silent-h/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 23:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/11/14/tales-of-a-silent-h/</guid>
      <description>For whatever reason, I was inspired to start playing with logo designs. There&amp;rsquo;s no new decisions to be seen here in this post, just some ideas I&amp;rsquo;m playing with (and rejecting).
I actually used to make my own typography and font designs, one such example is this:
You can see more examples of prior logos here.
For the past 5 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this:
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really liked it, but it was good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automobiles, Interviews, all Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 22:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</guid>
      <description>To say 2010 has been a busy year would be an understatement.
While we were all waiting for Apple to confirm the existence of the iPad, I was busy tweaking, improving, and porting my game Smiles to a bunch of new platforms. The most significant port by far was to Netbook PCs for Intel&amp;rsquo;s AppUp Center, a brand new App Store coming soon to Netbooks everywhere.
To say Intel and AppUp have been good to me, that would be another understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles HD bug list (and launch day thoughts)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/03/smiles-hd-bug-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 22:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/03/smiles-hd-bug-list/</guid>
      <description>Wow! So that was iPad launch day.
I&amp;rsquo;ll talk a little more about the “day 1 FREE” experiment after some results. Just before disappearing, the game was sitting at #60 in the Top FREE Apps (#13 Top FREE Games). Earlier today, I caught it at #55. Anyways, I said I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to talk about this!
Like many other developers, I shipped the game to Apple for launch day without actually testing it on a real device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramping up for iPad: Smiles HD</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</guid>
      <description>Alright! The iPad is coming soon, as is a brand new version of Smiles.
As we speak I&amp;rsquo;m putting the finishing touches on Smiles HD, the all new higher resolution and slightly redesigned iPhone game coming soon to the iPad.
Now, in the eyes of Apple I&amp;rsquo;m nobody special. So like many of you, I&amp;rsquo;ll be heading down to my local Apple store on launch day to pick me up an iPad&amp;hellip; with one slight difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen FREE ZEN WEEKEND download stats</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/01/smiles-zen-free-download-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 13:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/11/01/smiles-zen-free-download-stats/</guid>
      <description>I figure there&amp;rsquo;s no reason not to share these.
Smiles Zen‘s “FREE ZEN WEEKEND” download statistics:
 1022 – Thursday October 29th (started at noon) 3544 – Friday October 30th 1826 – Saturday October 31st 1361 – Sunday November 1st 144 – Monday November 2nd (ended at 1 AM)
 The 29th was a fraction of a day. I flipped the switch roughly around noon, which kicked in about 4 hours later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Mushrooms and Logo Tests</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/07/21/animated-mushrooms-and-logo-tests/</guid>
      <description>Been caught up with a number of things. Here&amp;rsquo;s one I&amp;rsquo;m rather proud of, an animated Smiles mushroom animation.
Click for 400k animated gif
Animated in ToonBoom Studio.
Something else, an updated Sykhronics Logo animation.
That one is me goofing off in Sony Vegas.
Fun fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The shelf-life of Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 14:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Smiles has been available for nearly 6 months in the App Store now. From the stories you may have heard, not all iPhone titles necessarily do well. But if you consider that the game was developed by one person in 4 months, it lives under the charts, and has only 1 Apple mention to it&amp;rsquo;s name, it&amp;rsquo;s actually done alright. I&amp;rsquo;m hardly “rolling in the dough”, but I can make ends meet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GDC and IGF Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 06:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Just a few hours ago I could barely move. Nearly crawling my way out of bed to attack the day (ahem&amp;hellip; night), after the long flight home.
I&amp;rsquo;ve since returned to my regular routine of pacing around my studio (i.e. basement), between moments of awe e-mailing and ranting everywhere it seems appropriate (forums, twitter). As I exhausted all those wonderful forms of communication, it seemed to be right time to start the required retrospective post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile: Friday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 20:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</guid>
      <description>Friday was the short day. Wednesday and Thursday we exhibited 10-6, where Friday was 10-3. Went back to the hotel and vegged that day, before heading back out to hang with the Fantastic Contraption guys.
My neighbors were the Secret Exit guys. I ended up spending a bulk of the show goofing off with Tuukka, an artist on Zen Bound. The Secret Exit guys refer to him as the “prankster” of the bunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile: Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 01:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>First day of exhibiting. I have to say, I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted. Feet ached, and limped a bit throughout the day, but I loved it.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few photos of the completed setup.
And a little closer.
I&amp;rsquo;m sharing a hotel with Phil Hassey of Galcon fame, and he had an amusing idea about creating some cheap signage. Hilighers and posterboard. At his booth he has a nicely done caracture of his goat Cuzco with a very supermarket-like sign advertising his sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile: Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Live from San Fransisco, it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; me.
As you may or may not have heard, I didn&amp;rsquo;t win. But that&amp;rsquo;s alright, I&amp;rsquo;m still here to exhibit.
We&amp;rsquo;re sharing booth space with the IGF main competition entrants, which is great. That way, when people come to see the cool IGF games, they&amp;rsquo;ll find us too. Here&amp;rsquo;s my slice.
Other cool stuff, Apple put up a page of us IGF Mobile entries. Very awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to the IGF (Mobile) Video: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/19/road-to-the-igf-mobile-video-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 01:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/03/19/road-to-the-igf-mobile-video-part-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m ready for GDC!
Come take an early look at the madness I&amp;rsquo;m bringing with me to the conference.
As you can probably guess from the lack of Smiles PC/HD progress posts, I will not be demoing it at the conference. I am still bringing both laptops though. The big one will be doing something else instead.
Enjoy! 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to the IGF (Mobile) Video: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/27/road-to-the-igf-mobile-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/27/road-to-the-igf-mobile-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yet another series, but video.
Part 1 of hopefully a few videos of me showing off my IGF preparations. Sinage, computers, etc.
3 weeks left and counting.
A bit roughly put together, but that&amp;rsquo;s half the point. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want it to eat up that much time, though it did take me some time to remember how to edit and encode a video (without my software crashing).
It&amp;rsquo;s no Goo Road to the IGF, but hey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cheerfully Blunt Road Map</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 01:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</guid>
      <description>Alright, so the clock says it&amp;rsquo;s Friday now. According to my whiteboard, that&amp;rsquo;s 29 days before I leave for the Game Developers Conference. Between now and then, I have a few commitments to take care of. Possibly a 2nd draft for my writing engagement, jury (selection?) duty, in addition to IGF preparations. It&amp;rsquo;s also an important turning point for Smiles as a product and a brand. Lets talk about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles nominated for Best Casual Game</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/31/smiles-nominated-for-best-casual-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 17:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/31/smiles-nominated-for-best-casual-game/</guid>
      <description>As the title says, Smiles is a finalist for Best Casual Game of 2008 on BestAppEver.com.
Visit this link and give it a vote.
http://bestappever.com/v/gcas
Thanks! 😀
And a reminder, Smiles Drop is on sale for $1.99 (reg $2.99) until the end of the day new years.
http://www.newyearappblowout.com
EDIT: The Smiles Drop sale is extended until Sunday the 4th. Sunday night though, it&amp;rsquo;s going back up.
Whee. 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smile Zen and Drop Available, News</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 02:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/12/05/smile-zen-and-drop-available-news/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 2 weeks, and much has happened.
As the topic suggests, Smiles Drop and Smiles Zen are now both available. $2.99 each, or save $1 by getting Smiles ($4.99).
So yeah, in a way that means I technically have 3 games out. As for blog content, I&amp;rsquo;m half way through a post on what went in to creating the video. Actually I was half through the Friday of the last post, but got caught up in the fact that I could actually take it easy for a couple days&amp;hellip; and I sorta haven&amp;rsquo;t gone back to finish the post yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, a weekend</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/21/finally-a-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2008 23:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/21/finally-a-weekend/</guid>
      <description>I just finished up the other half of the game split a couple hours ago, “Smiles Drop”. It needs some testing first, but it should be off to Apple early/mid next week.
So here we are. Just over 3 weeks after finishing Smiles. Finished a video, finished a web site, finished a press release, finished contacting the websites, and now finished my releases for the next couple weeks.
Wow&amp;hellip; I think I can finally take a weekend off now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Zen submitted to Apple</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 22:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/20/smiles-zen-submitted-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>Part one of my rebellion against the iPhone price drop madness has begun. Smiles Zen, the standalone version of Zen is now sent to Apple.
If everything goes according to plan, it will be released bright and early Tuesday morning. This time, I explicitly set the date.
– – – – – – –
In other news, a new review.
http://osxreality.com/&amp;hellip;/a-relaxing-matching-game-with-fun-graphics/
OSX Reality – 4 Stars. Incredibly favorable review. Their only beef was that they expect a price drop for it to be competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Website Update</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/16/smiles-website-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 01:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/16/smiles-website-update/</guid>
      <description>One thing lead to another, and I updated the Smiles website. It now has a fancy header, and a bit of a hint at what I&amp;rsquo;ll be up to in the coming weeks.
http://www.smiles-game.com
It also seems my press release/pack was picked up by 1up.
http://www.1up.com/do/gameOverview?cId=3169760
And that&amp;rsquo;s it for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Marketing Week</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/14/smiles-marketing-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 18:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/14/smiles-marketing-week/</guid>
      <description>And that about wraps up marketing week.
After finishing and finally getting the video uploaded Sunday night, Monday began my marketing blitz.
The day started well, with the almighty Tim taking the first initiative and sharing the video.
http://www.indiegames.com/blog/&amp;hellip;
The rest of the Think Services network picked up on the FingerGaming review as part of the usual syndication.
Game Set Watch | GamaSutra
And continuing with Think Services, I entered the game in the IGF Mobile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sykhronics grins on to iPhone with Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/12/sykhronics-grins-on-to-iphone-with-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 12:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/12/sykhronics-grins-on-to-iphone-with-smiles/</guid>
      <description>London, Ontario, Canada – November 12th, 2008
Sykhronics Entertainment would like to introduce, Smiles. A brand new game now available for iPhone and iPod touch.
Smiles is a collection of 2 great games.
Smiles Drop is an unconventional action puzzle game. Unlike many others, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait to make your next move. In addition, you&amp;rsquo;re not pressured in to making that move either. Play at your own pace. Make matches, break ice and rocks, twisting and turning your way to higher scores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Smiles Hands on Video</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/10/final-smiles-hands-on-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/10/final-smiles-hands-on-video/</guid>
      <description>Final version of the Smiles video. It&amp;rsquo;s the short one again, but with me talking.
Here&amp;rsquo;s your chance to hear and mock Mike. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a number of positive and amusing comments from the video. Such fun things as that I sound like an Infomercial host, and music sounds like “corporate training music”. Finishing this video has been an incredible hassle. Hard drives dying, frequent reboots, loss of WAV file playback in Windows, and YouTube difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles hands on video now available</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/03/smiles-hands-on-video-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 02:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/11/03/smiles-hands-on-video-now-available/</guid>
      <description>One of two promotional videos I&amp;rsquo;m making. This one is the “hands on” one, requiring a silly looking “camera on tripod hugging thing” to collect all the footage.
Viddler Long Version: http://www.viddler.com/&amp;hellip;/19/
Youtube Short Version: http://www.youtube.com/E4sUK241aRA
Youtube Long Version: http://www.youtube.com/nEO1-zybCU4
In this video, I&amp;rsquo;m unfortunately assuming the player will pick up on all the nice things why this isn&amp;rsquo;t a Bejeweled clone. But to be sure, I&amp;rsquo;m going to spell it out next video, and briefly mention some of things not covered here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Press Pack now online</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-press-pack-now-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 20:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-press-pack-now-online/</guid>
      <description>A press pack is now available for Smiles. Hit the website, it&amp;rsquo;s currently linked from the front page. Refresh if you don&amp;rsquo;t see it.
http://www.smiles-game.com
Screen shots and high-res logo and promo artwork.
Video is in progress. Hopefully by the end of the day Friday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles is Gold</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-is-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2008 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/30/smiles-is-gold/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from the grocery store, and got the word. “Ready for Sale“.
http://appshopper.com/games/smiles
Search for “Smiles” and scroll down a bit, or browse the puzzle or strategy categories in iTunes.
Contrary to the description, it&amp;rsquo;s an Action Puzzler. Lumines/Metoes ‘esc, or Bejeweled on crack.
Thanks to some fancy design kung fu, it&amp;rsquo;s also what the description says. But that&amp;rsquo;s a topic all in itself.
– – – –</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles sent to Apple</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/28/smiles-sent-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 07:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/28/smiles-sent-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d love to say the wait is over, but now we start the next wait. Waiting for approval.
As of 7:45 AM this Tuesday October 28th morning, the game is now sent.
– – – – – – –
Digging through my SVN logs for some stats.
Repository was created on June 22nd, 2008. That&amp;rsquo;s a total of 4 months and 6 days.
All code, art (except the original TTF font, though I did design and make the logo text), and audio created by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I love the TRC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/26/i-love-the-trc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 06:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/26/i-love-the-trc/</guid>
      <description>Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s been so long.
The last game I did TRC for was Atomic Betty, the Gameboy Advance game I worked on before leaving Big Blue Bubble. That would have been some time during July of 2005. That finished up, and I was a free man for August 1st.
By TRC I mean Technical Requirements Checklist. Every platform holder has them, though they sometimes have a different name for them. A TRC is a combination of guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Candidate 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 04:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/10/25/release-candidate-1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s late, now 5 AM Saturday morning. Release Candidate 1 is just a few hours away. Some achievement tweaks, and minor bugs and we&amp;rsquo;re good.
Should go out to Apple on Monday afternoon. Then probably a week and it&amp;rsquo;ll be live in the App Store.
I&amp;rsquo;d have taken a photo, but I&amp;rsquo;m currently cameraless.
– – – –
The dummy website for the game:
http://www.smiles-game.com
Some time after it goes out, I&amp;rsquo;ll make a proper site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Indie Office, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/13/the-indie-office-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 03:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/13/the-indie-office-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Hypothetical situation.
Note: Try to refrain from bombard me with requests yet, &amp;lsquo;cause I know a lot of people already like this idea.
cough, I&amp;rsquo;m in London, Ontario, Canada.A typical game company places 10 or more people under the same roof. Office space rented out at the expense of the company. There&amp;rsquo;s a management hierarchy, one or more people responsible for business and infrastructure aspects of the company, and an arrangement of programmers, artists, designers, possibly testers and a sound guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficult Names = Bad?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/27/difficult-names-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2007 09:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/27/difficult-names-bad/</guid>
      <description>Lets try a little experiment. (Try to) read this.
Sykhronics Entertainment Anyone that&amp;rsquo;s followed my work probably won&amp;rsquo;t be miffed by that mean looking first word. But if you stuck around, you stuck around for my work, not my clever name. You probably have your own pronunciation of it too. I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly heard some interesting ones from telemarketers that whois&amp;rsquo;d my domains for a phone number.
Lets see if we are thinking the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Methods</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/17/testing-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2007 20:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/17/testing-methods/</guid>
      <description>This is from a forum post I made in response to a question on testing methods. A classic Mike random advice assault. This branched off to a series of thoughts on built in game recorders.
– – – –
Free testing methods:
Peer testing has worked well for me, as developers tend to have bizarre PC configurations (multiple monitors, multiple gamepads, etc). There&amp;rsquo;s also a level of critique a developer can give that goes above and beyond, but you need to be clear and capable of asking for the harshest of critiques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitch Video Trailer Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/02/19/pitch-video-trailer-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 22:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/02/19/pitch-video-trailer-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>I was busy last month cutting together a trailer for&amp;hellip; business purposes. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about this later. It turned out surprisingly more difficult that I had have hoped, but I found a rather unique way of pulling it together.
Obviously, the secret weapon is Fraps. Trying to nab constant 60fps footage was doable, but proved tricky, due to my hard drives not being the most defragged. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many takes later, I ended up with nearly an hour of game footage, that was cut down to a 4 minute presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Illustrator or Animator needed</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/30/2d-illustrator-or-animator-needed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2007 18:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/30/2d-illustrator-or-animator-needed/</guid>
      <description>This posting has been filled. Thanks everyone.
– – – –
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little job posting that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to circulate.
[edit] Edited, &amp;lsquo;cause it was rather technical and mean sounding. – – – –
Hi there,
We&amp;rsquo;re looking for a skilled 2D illustrator or animator for a 2 month contract, to start some time in February. The work can be done remotely. This is a full time contract, and I expect it to be on par with industry wages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketches and Website 2007</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/06/sketches-and-website-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 12:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/06/sketches-and-website-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m actively preparing for &amp;hellip; some event. On my to-do list for this miraculous day, is cleaning up the web sites. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finished 1 so far, the Sykhronics web site.
www.sykhronics.com
It&amp;rsquo;s not functional, but I think it looks cooler/more professional than before. I&amp;rsquo;ll make it usable at some later date.
Since it&amp;rsquo;s a new month, here&amp;rsquo;s a couple notable images from last month. The first is are a little sketch I did for each of my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s in their Christmas cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teenage Indie Game Dev Ninja Turtle</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/teenage-indie-game-dev-ninja-turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/07/22/teenage-indie-game-dev-ninja-turtle/</guid>
      <description>I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in games a long time. Doing “amazing” things with “PRINT” on the Commodore 64 at the age of 9, and promoting a cheesy Zelda/Final Fantasy hybrid online at 16. Just to give some perspective, the year was 1996, and the game was called Legends of Tidal, a game the Internet has forgotten. Then there was all that game industry experience, but pshaw, nobody cares about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google knows...</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/google-knows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 23:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/google-knows/</guid>
      <description>One way to know if you&amp;rsquo;re established on the net.
I can&amp;rsquo;t even remember what it used to recommend instead of Sykhronics, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have finally made an impact. Woo. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Sykoland</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/welcome-to-sykoland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 00:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/04/welcome-to-sykoland/</guid>
      <description>And here we are. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s the start of a more regular practice. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably read the brief Manifesto to the right. This was written some 9 months ago. And now, since things are a tad more orderly, it&amp;rsquo;s time to expand on that.
Sykhronics, pronounced “psi-cron-icks”. A branding of Mike Kasprzak&amp;rsquo;s independent game works. Established in 1998, replacing my older branding Gamma Flare Games. After bouncing around the gracious hosting of a few friends, I acquired the “dot com” in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logo Rhythm</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/logo-rhythm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 21:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/logo-rhythm/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot going on, which I&amp;rsquo;ll go in to in further posts. This one&amp;rsquo;s on Logos.
Way back in July I dropped a note about some Rejected Logos. I still haven&amp;rsquo;t decided what I want, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been back playing the logo making game.
Ahh yes, a smooth graphic design&amp;rsquo;ish logo. Hurah.
Do I like it? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I&amp;rsquo;m torn between going with something more cartoony, or including a little face in the logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blam!  Teaser</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2005 10:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/04/blam-teaser/</guid>
      <description>So begins the campaign. PuffBOMB.com/.net/.org are now online with this wonderful tease site. I&amp;rsquo;ll have banners show up in the indie world soon, just to build some awareness. I have some big plans for this game.
IGF polishing goes well. Just a few more graphics, and some minor updates to the game itself, and we&amp;rsquo;re good to go.
2 days left. We&amp;rsquo;re looking good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected Logos</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/01/rejected-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 03:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/01/rejected-logos/</guid>
      <description>On a mission to build corporate identity, the trials and tribulations of logo design. Given that introduction, &amp;hellip; yeah, I was playing with logo design ideas. At the end of the day, I didn&amp;rsquo;t exactly come up with something to use. None the less, this is my blog, and I feel compelled to share it with myself, and any other misguided net travelers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s “Ghastly logo“. For my own amusement, you can see it&amp;rsquo;s evolution below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>