<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 21:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>State of the Investigation</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2013/05/10/state-of-the-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 21:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2013/05/10/state-of-the-investigation/</guid>
      <description>So I’ve done a few scatterbrained posts lately that talk about things. Most of them had rather open ended conclusions, that were followed by wildly out-of-left field follow up posts. Here’s me making sense of that.
Evaluating Middlewares: Unity does good 3D, bad at JS Unity’s “JavaScript” isn’t JavaScript, it’s better named UnityScript. UnityScript is kinda terrible, essentially being just a different syntaxed less featured C#. But var is allowed, so uhhh… *shrug*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation: Business and Fear</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/conversation-business-and-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 01:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/20/conversation-business-and-fear/</guid>
      <description>From Monday, Gianfranco (whom I abbreviate as GB) was concerned that some of the guys might have been fear-mongering after a recent set of very sad sad videos. That catapulted me in to a rant about… well… yeah, it’s actually that way. Indie truths a-plenty.
The first begins on the subject of “big games are extremely risky”, despite doing one myself right now.
I had some upload issues with the prior video, which lead me to watching my video a few more times, and expanding on the subject of indies and failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: The Indie Indie Conversation</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/07/19/introducing-the-indie-indie-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! I figured now was a good time to talk about a project I’ve been involved with for the past couple months now. Something we like to call, the Indie Indie Conversation. The conversation is a YouTube channel shared amongst a group of indie game developers where we talk about what we do, the challenges, and the lifestyle of creating games independently for a living.
I’ve personally failed many attempts at starting a regular video log here on my blog, and in retrospect that may have been the uncomfortable feeling of “talking to a wall”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramping up for iPad: Smiles HD</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 12:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/19/ramping-up-for-ipad-smiles-hd/</guid>
      <description>Alright! The iPad is coming soon, as is a brand new version of Smiles.
As we speak I’m putting the finishing touches on Smiles HD, the all new higher resolution and slightly redesigned iPhone game coming soon to the iPad.
Now, in the eyes of Apple I’m nobody special. So like many of you, I’ll be heading down to my local Apple store on launch day to pick me up an iPad… with one slight difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Smiles, Part 0</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 04:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</guid>
      <description>I know my track record for completing a blog series is pretty lousy, but this one should be easier. I kept a personal log with pictures during the development of Smiles, so most of the work is done for me. I just need need to go through it and regurgitate my notes.
To start, I’m going to give a bit of insight in to what happened when I stopped writing my Engines, Names and Evolution blog series last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar Magnet</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2008/02/29/sugar-magnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Feb 2008 22:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2008/02/29/sugar-magnet/</guid>
      <description>February 29th! How could I not say something today.
Just what to say is the question.
Blogging in the past, I’ve noticed the tendency to want to turn the blog in to something. A community, articles and subjects, talk-back, and all that stuff. And that’s great and all, but it’s a lot of work for not much return. Traditionally to make ends meet this way, you plaster your blog with advertisements, or actively soliciting contract work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO got you down? Bring down Unrated.</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/21/ao-got-you-down-bring-down-unrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 14:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/21/ao-got-you-down-bring-down-unrated/</guid>
      <description>The AO games rating seem to be the hot topic as of late, thanks to Rockstar’s Manhunt 2 initially netting the rating. The AO rating is terrible for game, because it excludes you from key retail outlets like Walmart.
But I want to bring your attention to something that’s generally being overlooked by these articles. Films in the same genre as the Manhunt game. Hostel and Saw. Torture films basically. Hey look!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secrets of the &amp;#8220;Umihara Kawase&amp;#8221; rope</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/14/the-secrets-of-the-umihara-kawase-rope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 22:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/14/the-secrets-of-the-umihara-kawase-rope/</guid>
      <description>Raigan and I have had an extremely brief dialog on in game ropes. It makes sense, for a while we were both doing rope driven games.
Well, due to my failings as a communicator, I sort of just never got back to him. Yet, I absolutely love the topic, and certainly spent much time puzzled by it. Apparently I’ve also made the conscious effort to push my way in to obscurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &amp;#8220;Indie Office&amp;#8221;, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/13/the-indie-office-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 03:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/06/13/the-indie-office-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Hypothetical situation.
Note: Try to refrain from bombard me with requests yet, ’cause I know a lot of people already like this idea.
cough, I’m in London, Ontario, Canada.A typical game company places 10 or more people under the same roof. Office space rented out at the expense of the company. There’s a management hierarchy, one or more people responsible for business and infrastructure aspects of the company, and an arrangement of programmers, artists, designers, possibly testers and a sound guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplification</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/12/simplification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 04:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/12/simplification/</guid>
      <description>I think it’s an important direction and discussion for game design. Sure, as a gamer, I can handle complicated control schemes. I’ve done my time and held my own in hotkey crazy RTS’s, twitch FPS’s, and I can be pretty menacing in Tony Hawk. But most of these games aren’t getting any easier. I don’t even care to finish Tony Hawk’s Project 8, or the Underground games, because the things you need to do at the end are ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deskonomics: Shape</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/21/deskonomics-shape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 08:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/21/deskonomics-shape/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a fun point. Almost everyone works at a desk, but nobody talks about desks. Chairs come up sometimes, especially in discussions about the Aeron chair versus a well made leather, or general sitting ergonomics.
This is an incredibly broad topic that could easily span dozens of blog posts in it’s complexity. Game developers and other media professionals have many needs for their working surface. And depending on how many hats you wear as a developer, you’ve got to fit several monitors, speakers (stereo or surround), input devices (keyboards, mice, tablets, midi interfaces), scanners, printers, and other office friendly objects (fans, phones, paper and supplies) on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Big Planet</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/09/little-big-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 03:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/03/09/little-big-planet/</guid>
      <description>The innovative games arms race is on.
http://gamevideos.com/video/id/9860
… Alright, I give up.
Normally when I see a really fantastic game like this, I’m all excited (Spore). This one drove me in to a brief game design depression. Now that’s emergent gameplay at it’s finest, and I’ve not even played the game.
Concepts like collaborative editing and modern user friendly editing. Two ideas I’ve been extremely excited about toying with. “Oh, we do them both”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was fun while it lasted</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/10/it-was-fun-while-it-lasted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 21:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/01/10/it-was-fun-while-it-lasted/</guid>
      <description>I like Slamdance. I entered PuffBOMB last year, and was a finalist for the casual game award. Since then, I’ve been excited that a more “artful” game competition was beginning to take off. Winners receive a funky ugly dog statuette. Cool! Then a controversial game was pulled. Things are not going well now.
It’s a real shame, and I hope something good comes from the controversy, rather than developing in to more Jack Thompson style heat for our industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XNA 360 Indie Kit Hooray&amp;#8230; C# !?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/08/14/xna-360-indie-kit-hooray-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 05:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/08/14/xna-360-indie-kit-hooray-c/</guid>
      <description>I tend not to go off on news topics, but ‘ehh… today’s special. No doubt you’ve heard about Microsoft’s big news that’s making Indie developers all giddy. $99 a year to “activate” an Xbox 360 so that you can test your games on it. Sounds great, but there’s 1 little thing that could pose a problem for some.
C#
… Alright. Nothing against C# as a language, ’cause I’m sure it’s a great and efficient once you get used to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to annoy the Internet</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/11/how-to-annoy-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2006 03:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/11/how-to-annoy-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>A condensed version of my previous post seemed to be making the rounds. It’s resulted in several interesting comments and additions from developers and gamers alike. I’ve decided to do your homework, and compile this list. Text in bold are the originals, with my comments in normal type.
Here we go.
—
GameProducer.net additions:
—
10. Resize and move all the previously opened windows to the upper-left corner of the screen after returning from full-screen mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 ways to annoy the panel</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/06/8-ways-to-annoy-the-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2006 16:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/06/8-ways-to-annoy-the-panel/</guid>
      <description>Now that I’ve succeeded in world domination (also known as syndication), I present to you a short list of complaints to fellow developers. 8 ways to make the monthly round-up panel hate you. Unofficial in every way, as it’s just my observations, but toned a tad sarcastic and sharp to get the point across. It’s not for everyone, as we do get a good number of games that work great. But there’s just enough of them to compel me to write this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGF and PuffBOMB clones?</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 12:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</guid>
      <description>Well, well. The IGF 2006 Entries are now online, and we have a PuffBOMB clone to duel with. Impulse. It appers to be, according to the description, pretty much the same idea. Lets quote.
 Impulse: The player must place bombs and adjust their timers to make a ball hit the goal field. Obstacles, special elements and force fields provide varied levels. An interactive timeline helps controlling the game by jumping to specific times and guarantees a flexible and unique gameplay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>