<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nostalgia on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://new.toonormal.com/categories/nostalgia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nostalgia on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 05:57:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://new.toonormal.com/categories/nostalgia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Five years as a full-time Indie</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/12/03/five-years-as-a-full-time-indie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 05:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/12/03/five-years-as-a-full-time-indie/</guid>
      <description>The exact timing is a little off, but I today just renewed my business license.
Yes, 5 years ago July I left my job as Technical Director at Big Blue Bubble (now one of Canada’s largest game studios … you’re welcome ;)). Here’s what I had to say.
 All systems are go!
  July 29th, 2005 – 10:34 PM
Amazing. Today was my official last day at Big Blue Bubble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teenage Indie Game Dev Ninja Turtle</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/07/22/teenage-indie-game-dev-ninja-turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 18:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/07/22/teenage-indie-game-dev-ninja-turtle/</guid>
      <description>I guess I’ve been involved in games a long time. Doing “amazing” things with “PRINT” on the Commodore 64 at the age of 9, and promoting a cheesy Zelda/Final Fantasy hybrid online at 16. Just to give some perspective, the year was 1996, and the game was called Legends of Tidal, a game the Internet has forgotten. Then there was all that game industry experience, but pshaw, nobody cares about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Logos</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/11/27/classic-logos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 03:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/11/27/classic-logos/</guid>
      <description>Whilst writing my recent post on the updated logo for the business transition of the branding, I was inspired to take a look at the progression of Sykhronics logos over the years. Some of the more recent logos are custom designed fonts, which is something I plan to again some day with the logo.
Kenny Thornton, and the guys at Execute (a long since abandoned group). Kenny was the only one to ever release anything under the branding, so it’s pretty much his.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>