<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IGF on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://new.toonormal.com/categories/igf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IGF on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://new.toonormal.com/categories/igf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Because We May Sale</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2012/05/25/because-we-may-sale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://new.toonormal.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/Atwx4_gCIAAQ5Hq.jpg-larg2e.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.becausewemay.com&#34;&gt;Because We May&lt;/a&gt;, a grandiose cross platform mega sale is on right now. Android, iPad, iPhone, PC (Desura), and Blackberry Playbook versions of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smileshd.com&#34;&gt;Smiles and Smiles HD&lt;/a&gt; are all heavily discounted and available for about $2. The sale ends June 1st.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike the Multi-Winner and GDC Champion</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</guid>
      <description>So, holy cow! GDC was absolutely insane! I almost don’t know where to start, but lets start from the beginning.
First thing first, I won again!!
Yes, as if winning a free car wasn’t enough, I also won a free trip to GDC. So Intel ended up covering my flight, putting me up in a fancy hotel, gave me some spending money, treating me to dinner, AND giving me nearly front row seats to a San Jose Sharks hockey game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare 16 Results are Live!</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/01/04/ludum-dare-16-results-are-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 12:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/01/04/ludum-dare-16-results-are-live/</guid>
      <description>I know it’s hard to compete with the wake of the IGF Finalists announcement yesterday, but the Ludum Dare 16 winners were announced yesterday too.
Go here for the Top 20:
http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-16/?action=top
Here for the categorical listings:
http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/ludum-dare-16/
And here for the news post:
http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/2010/01/03/ludum-dare-16-results/
Trying to compete with the IGF Buzz would be silly, so I’m going to push back my little LD retrospective until things are a little more calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike&amp;#8217;s 2009</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 19:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2010/01/01/mikes-2009/</guid>
      <description>So wow. That’s finally it for 2009. Like doing taxes ever year, I feel a special sort of obligation that I write some sort of retrospective, especially after such an eventful year as this one. Far more awesome than taxes. 😉
I wasn’t sure where to start, so I ended up categorizing aspects of the year. I’ll free form rant about each topic as I come to it.
Let’s begin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The shelf-life of Smiles</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 14:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/04/17/the-shelf-life-of-smiles/</guid>
      <description>Smiles has been available for nearly 6 months in the App Store now. From the stories you may have heard, not all iPhone titles necessarily do well. But if you consider that the game was developed by one person in 4 months, it lives under the charts, and has only 1 Apple mention to it’s name, it’s actually done alright. I’m hardly “rolling in the dough”, but I can make ends meet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles Statistics at GDC</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/04/07/smiles-statistics-at-gdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 22:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/04/07/smiles-statistics-at-gdc/</guid>
      <description>For GDC, I decided to make a special version of Smiles. On the surface it would look like the Lite version (Free Smiles), except I re-enabled statistic tracking and high scores.
Here is how the visitors at my IGF kiosk did.
General Statistics
Total Time Played: 7 hours, 39 minutes
Games Played: 131
Zen Statistics
Total Time Playing: 4 hour, 12 minutes
Games Played: 78
Games Won: 33
Total Moves: 2640</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GDC and IGF Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 06:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/30/the-gdc-and-igf-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Just a few hours ago I could barely move. Nearly crawling my way out of bed to attack the day (ahem… night), after the long flight home.
I’ve since returned to my regular routine of pacing around my studio (i.e. basement), between moments of awe e-mailing and ranting everywhere it seems appropriate (forums, twitter). As I exhausted all those wonderful forms of communication, it seemed to be right time to start the required retrospective post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Friday</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 20:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/28/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-friday/</guid>
      <description>Friday was the short day. Wednesday and Thursday we exhibited 10-6, where Friday was 10-3. Went back to the hotel and vegged that day, before heading back out to hang with the Fantastic Contraption guys.
My neighbors were the Secret Exit guys. I ended up spending a bulk of the show goofing off with Tuukka, an artist on Zen Bound. The Secret Exit guys refer to him as the “prankster” of the bunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 01:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/26/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>First day of exhibiting. I have to say, I’m exhausted. Feet ached, and limped a bit throughout the day, but I loved it.
Here’s a few photos of the completed setup.

And a little closer.

I’m sharing a hotel with Phil Hassey of Galcon fame, and he had an amusing idea about creating some cheap signage. Hilighers and posterboard. At his booth he has a nicely done caracture of his goat Cuzco with a very supermarket-like sign advertising his sale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiles at the IGF Mobile &amp;#8211; Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 01:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/25/smiles-at-the-igf-mobile-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Live from San Fransisco, it’s… me.
As you may or may not have heard, I didn’t win. But that’s alright, I’m still here to exhibit.
We’re sharing booth space with the IGF main competition entrants, which is great. That way, when people come to see the cool IGF games, they’ll find us too. Here’s my slice.

Other cool stuff, Apple put up a page of us IGF Mobile entries. Very awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to the IGF (Mobile) Video &amp;#8211; Part 2</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/19/road-to-the-igf-mobile-video-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 01:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/03/19/road-to-the-igf-mobile-video-part-2/</guid>
      <description>I’m back. This time, I’m ready for GDC!
Come take an early look at the madness I’m bringing with me to the conference.
As you can probably guess from the lack of Smiles PC/HD progress posts, I will not be demoing it at the conference. I am still bringing both laptops though. The big one will be doing something else instead.
Enjoy! 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to the IGF (Mobile) Video &amp;#8211; Part 1</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/02/27/road-to-the-igf-mobile-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 22:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/02/27/road-to-the-igf-mobile-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yet another series, but video.
Part 1 of hopefully a few videos of me showing off my IGF preparations. Sinage, computers, etc.
3 weeks left and counting.
A bit roughly put together, but that’s half the point. I didn’t want it to eat up that much time, though it did take me some time to remember how to edit and encode a video (without my software crashing).
It’s no Goo Road to the IGF, but hey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cheerfully Blunt Road Map</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 01:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/02/20/a-cheerfully-blunt-road-map/</guid>
      <description>Alright, so the clock says it’s Friday now. According to my whiteboard, that’s 29 days before I leave for the Game Developers Conference. Between now and then, I have a few commitments to take care of. Possibly a 2nd draft for my writing engagement, jury (selection?) duty, in addition to IGF preparations. It’s also an important turning point for Smiles as a product and a brand. Lets talk about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Smiles, Part 0</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 04:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2009/01/02/the-development-of-smiles-part-0/</guid>
      <description>I know my track record for completing a blog series is pretty lousy, but this one should be easier. I kept a personal log with pictures during the development of Smiles, so most of the work is done for me. I just need need to go through it and regurgitate my notes.
To start, I’m going to give a bit of insight in to what happened when I stopped writing my Engines, Names and Evolution blog series last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh hey look, it&amp;#8217;s IGF time</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/06/16/oh-hey-look-its-igf-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 03:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/06/16/oh-hey-look-its-igf-time/</guid>
      <description>Wow, and yikes. Time flies. IGF Submission time again. October 1st ‘eh? I should probably enter. shrug
Here’s something interesting.
 The 2008 IGF Main Competition will again be open to all independent developers to submit their games – whether it be on PC, console digital download, Web browser, or other more exotic formats.
 Cool, but doesn’t that have to mean your game is already available/to be available by October?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enjoy GDC 2007, Only $32</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/03/14/enjoy-gdc-2007-only-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 20:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/03/14/enjoy-gdc-2007-only-32/</guid>
      <description>I think I’ve already posted about this everywhere, except here. If you’re like me, and decided to skip out on Travel, Hotel, and admission to GDC, you can get the meat of the event for a fair $32.
GDC Radio Store
$8 gets you a day (about 6 hours of talks) for either the Indie Games Summit or the Casual Games Summit. Nice. Buy ‘em all for nearly 24 hours of interesting discussions and talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was fun while it lasted</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/01/10/it-was-fun-while-it-lasted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 21:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/01/10/it-was-fun-while-it-lasted/</guid>
      <description>I like Slamdance. I entered PuffBOMB last year, and was a finalist for the casual game award. Since then, I’ve been excited that a more “artful” game competition was beginning to take off. Winners receive a funky ugly dog statuette. Cool! Then a controversial game was pulled. Things are not going well now.
It’s a real shame, and I hope something good comes from the controversy, rather than developing in to more Jack Thompson style heat for our industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh right, a compilation too</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 10:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2007/01/07/oh-right-a-compilation-too/</guid>
      <description>It seems I missed the memo.
The 2nd Independent Games compilation was released back in September (25th), and that PuffBOMB game I seem to talk about all the time was included.
As well, there was a set of concept art included in the package. Said art can also be seen right here.
I suppose I should go find a way to acquire a copy, ’cause I’m not sure what happened to a complimentary one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday Morning GDC 2k6</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/03/23/thursday-morning-gdc-2k6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2006 09:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/03/23/thursday-morning-gdc-2k6/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, another big day at the Game Developers Conference.
Yesterday had some good events. The IGF results were announced, and the evil forces of Darwinia ran away with most of the prize money. Curse you Darwinia, I will have my revenge! Sony also spilled the beans, announcing a service “like” Xbox Live Arcade, but neglects to invite Indie’s. How rude. And everyone’s talking about Duke Nukem Forever 2.
It’ll be tough to beat a day as grand as yesterday, but today is always looking for a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamming from far away</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2006 00:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2006/01/28/slamming-from-far-away/</guid>
      <description>Slamdance was last week. PuffBOMB was a finalist for the PopCap award. A game by the name of Odyssey took the award. Congratz to them. The rest of the results can be found here.
It’s a shame, but I couldn’t make it out this year. That, and I’m still getting things off the ground here at Syko. I had heard from my “contact” there would be some PuffBOMB action at the festival, but so far my search for evidence has come up short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slamdance 2006 Casual Finalist</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 12:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/12/17/slamdance-2006-casual-finalist/</guid>
      <description>Not bad for a game originally created for a 48 hour competition. —
The 2006 PopCap Casual Game Award Finalists:
Cloud – Cloud
Joboo’s Gems – Gem Jocks
Ocular Ink – Pistachio Productions
The Odyssey – Liquid Dragon Studios
PuffBOMB – Sykhronics Entertainment
—
Press release can be found here.
In the unlikely circumstance that someone who’s actually attending reads my blog, I’d greatly appreciate any photos of the game at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The monkey that spits robots</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2005 08:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/12/15/the-monkey-that-spits-robots/</guid>
      <description>I’ve brought with me this horribly bright colored monster to burn your cornea. Hurah!
Right. Things are back and working in the Mike camp. Back to the grind and all. I’ve also recently finished a drawing pad, after slightly over 3 months. Doesn’t sound like much, but looking back it’s been taking me up to a year to fill one up.
So IGF finalists have been announced. Funky. So many great games have been coming out later in the year, I’m not surprised PuffBOMB didn’t place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGF and PuffBOMB clones?</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 12:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/21/igf-and-puffbomb-clones/</guid>
      <description>Well, well. The IGF 2006 Entries are now online, and we have a PuffBOMB clone to duel with. Impulse. It appers to be, according to the description, pretty much the same idea. Lets quote.
 Impulse: The player must place bombs and adjust their timers to make a ball hit the goal field. Obstacles, special elements and force fields provide varied levels. An interactive timeline helps controlling the game by jumping to specific times and guarantees a flexible and unique gameplay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&amp;#8217;s a Slamdance too?</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/15/theres-a-slamdance-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2005 06:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/15/theres-a-slamdance-too/</guid>
      <description>Apparently I forgot about this. The Slamdance Guerrilla Gamemaker Competition is yet another IGF like compo. I don’t think it’s actually worth any prizes… at least none their publicizing. Either way, I’ve put together a publicity pack for them, and will be sending it off today. A shame that they’re making me pay to enter. Buh.
I think what turned me off about this “way back when” was that the game had to be profitless, but apparently that’s not the case anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IGF, 117?</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/07/igf-117/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2005 14:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/07/igf-117/</guid>
      <description>Oh wow, the IGF is getting serious now. A news report on Gamasutra suggested that the IGF hit a record entry high of 117… Which is… many.
Like the dork I am, I’ll be monitoring this stuff. Don’t think this’ll be the last of my IGF rantings, oh no! Mwahaha!
Oh, and I’ve aparently become a big fan of incorrectly linking the IGF. Instead, I’ve found myself linking an equally prestigious organization, The Royal Society for the Relief of Indigent Gentlewomen of Scotland (Fund).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check, we&amp;#8217;re in</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/07/check-were-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2005 01:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/07/check-were-in/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, it seems I misplaced this blog post.
With less than 5 hours to spare, it’s in. Excellent. It wasn’t without it’s drama though. Once confirmed by myself, my brother, and a few friends that everything was good, I began to upload. *OH GOOD*, the upload server was acting up! Ack!
Within 20 minutes things cleared up. I snuck my game into it’s folder, hit the switch, and waited as it’s bytes were sucked out of Canada into some server likely in the California area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T minus 10, 9, 8, &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/06/t-minus-10-9-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 01:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/06/t-minus-10-9-8/</guid>
      <description>Clock is ticking.
Yep. In one sense, I’m ready to go. I filled out the submission for yesterday, and paid my entry fee. Apparently however, you need an installer. *Oh*. So today, after finishing the missing graphics, I got to do that. Huge thanks to Seth for sharing with me his NSIS script, which saved me hours of digging for little things like uninstaller cleanlyness, icon changing, and so many silly little things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrambled Eggs</title>
      <link>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/03/scrambled-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2005 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://new.toonormal.com/2005/09/03/scrambled-eggs/</guid>
      <description>A bit of a last minute scramble to get something together for the IGF. My original idea of getting the new game up and running, hahahaha… erm, sadly no. Progress is good, but not that good. However, I still am sending something. What I’m sending is the old PuffBOMB, from over 2 years ago, with a fresh paint job. The new look finally brings together my style ideas for the game from the past couple years It’s a chance to finally see it in action, and to know, does it suck or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>