<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The October Game on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/the-october-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The October Game on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 18:52:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/the-october-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Schedule Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/16/future-schedule-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 18:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/16/future-schedule-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now half way through the month, and progress on my “October Game” is minimal to say the least. I suppose that was to be expected, since I did have several things to finish this month. My week-days have been filled with various tasks, leaving only weekends to work on this new thing. Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll be busy with my “1 more thing”, leaving me the last week of October for a final crunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Game: Week 2 (more like day&#43;&#43;)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/11/october-game-week-2-more-like-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 00:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/11/october-game-week-2-more-like-day/</guid>
      <description>Busy busy. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to put much time in to the October game this week, but their certainly was progress.
Before:

and after&amp;hellip; some element are mocked up (character and outlining):

Day 3 – Back in the Saddle After a few days of other work (Smiles for Windows Phone 7), and making un-interactive interactive movies with silly internet tools, I have finally resumed working on my October game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Game: Week 1 (more like Weekend 1)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/04/october-game-week-1-more-like-weekend-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/10/04/october-game-week-1-more-like-weekend-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing my daily logs over at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/&#34;&gt;Ludum Dare site&lt;/a&gt;, to try and encourage more people to participate there. I&amp;rsquo;ve really only worked on the game for 2 days, despite my plans to start early. Today I was busy with &lt;em&gt;something else&lt;/em&gt;, so this week&amp;rsquo;s update will be light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “week” was about getting the foundation of editor up and running. Currently it works on a 2 button mouse (right click to erase), but the editing interface will support a touch screen (tile zero is the eraser). There&amp;rsquo;s currently no UI, but I can cycle tiles with the mouse wheel. It auto saves/loads the map to a specific file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started out looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/assets/uploads/2010/10/PoVGame03.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then by the end of the night Saturday, it looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.ludumdare.com/compo/assets/uploads/2010/10/PoVGame07.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested at all in the process from A to B, hit the jump for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; going to do some work today (Sunday), but there&amp;rsquo;s so little time left, I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a night early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My October Agenda</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/09/24/my-october-agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 23:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/09/24/my-october-agenda/</guid>
      <description>The response to the October Challenge has been incredible! I think the one thing that&amp;rsquo;s most amazing about it: everybody gets it. Every appearance of it on the internet has encouraged a plethora of “I&amp;rsquo;m in!” or “It&amp;rsquo;s ON like Donkey Kong!” responses. I&amp;rsquo;ve had dozens of direct tweets and people hunt me down in IRC just to tell me how much they love the idea. Very awesome!
For October 1st, I&amp;rsquo;ll be setting up and doing a new post on the Ludum Dare site, explaining how we can keep a list of finished games (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The October Challenge</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/09/23/the-october-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 02:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/09/23/the-october-challenge/</guid>
      <description>You might think I&amp;rsquo;m contractually obligated to start something ridiculous every few years, though I don&amp;rsquo;t remember signing the papers.
My new project is awesome, I love it, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to take me all of next year (and maybe more) to make it. I&amp;rsquo;m so fascinated and taken by it, it&amp;rsquo;s something I NEED to make. But that&amp;rsquo;s next years agenda.
This year, 2010, there&amp;rsquo;s still a good 3 months left.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>