<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDC on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/gdc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GDC on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 12:54:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/gdc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to GDC</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2011/02/26/off-to-gdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 12:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2011/02/26/off-to-gdc/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s mid-day Saturday. I&amp;rsquo;m on a plane in less than 20 hours bound for San Francisco, to join the celebration that is GDC (the Game Developer&amp;rsquo;s Conference).
It&amp;rsquo;s a packed week for me. The past couple years I attended back-to-back Indie Game Summit talks on Monday+Tuesday, but this year I&amp;rsquo;m planning to jump around a bit more. My iPod touch calendar is filled with the most interesting talks that my Summits pass will let me in to, including some Wednesday-&amp;gt;Friday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludum Dare #17, April 23rd-25th Weekend</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/15/ludum-dare-17-april-23rd-25th-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 12:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/15/ludum-dare-17-april-23rd-25th-weekend/</guid>
      <description>And it&amp;rsquo;s that time again too. Ludum Dare #17 is coming up next weekend. If the idea of crunching together a game from scratch in 48 hours interests you, check us out.
Now, this compo has been a little different. We announced our date nice and early, so the people at GDC would know about it, and to save us from silly “when will the compo be?” questions. So really, it was probably our best pre-announcement for a compo date to date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automobiles, Interviews, all Smiles</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 22:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/04/08/automobiles-interviews-all-smiles/</guid>
      <description>To say 2010 has been a busy year would be an understatement.
While we were all waiting for Apple to confirm the existence of the iPad, I was busy tweaking, improving, and porting my game Smiles to a bunch of new platforms. The most significant port by far was to Netbook PCs for Intel&amp;rsquo;s AppUp Center, a brand new App Store coming soon to Netbooks everywhere.
To say Intel and AppUp have been good to me, that would be another understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike the Multi-Winner and GDC Champion</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 05:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/18/mike-the-multi-winner-and-gdc-champion/</guid>
      <description>So, holy cow! GDC was absolutely insane! I almost don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start, but lets start from the beginning.
First thing first, I won again!!
Argh! They used that squished photo again! I even sent them a square one!
Yes, as if winning a free car wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, I also won a free trip to GDC. So Intel ended up covering my flight, putting me up in a fancy hotel, gave me some spending money, treating me to dinner, AND giving me nearly front row seats to a San Jose Sharks hockey game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike&#39;s GDC 2010 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/06/mikes-gdc-2010-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2010 07:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/06/mikes-gdc-2010-schedule/</guid>
      <description>For the benefit of friends and people I&amp;rsquo;m meeting at the show, here&amp;rsquo;s a run down of my itinerary for GDC. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be tweeting and watching twitter while I&amp;rsquo;m down for any impromptu meets, hang-outs, and whatever with people I know. If the twitter says “totally bored”, then you know. 🙂
If anybody I know needs my cell number, send me a quick e-mail (mike AT sykhronics dot com). It&amp;rsquo;s not my usual cell, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be my number whilst I&amp;rsquo;m in San Fran.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalizing your GDC pass</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 22:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/03/04/personalizing-your-gdc-pass/</guid>
      <description>Ordinarily, greeting someone by glancing at their chest might be seen as a little rude (especially a lady), but at GDC it&amp;rsquo;s encouraged! Yes I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the passes, not making a pass.
The passes do a good job of helping you connect a face to a name, and even a company, but you don&amp;rsquo;t always know who made or represents what. GDC passes include a relatively large pocket, so you could either make something to insert behind your name card, or cover the pass with some strategically placed stickers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Different GDC (for me)</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2010/02/27/a-very-different-gdc-for-me/</guid>
      <description>So last year, I was an IGF Mobile finalist. This little game of mine stood alongside iPhone favorites like Edge and Fieldrunners, vying for the “Best Mobile Game” award. And if I had won, &amp;hellip; well, I have no idea. Even just being a finalist has been great for me, so I&amp;rsquo;d image it would have been MORE great. 😉
That was 2009, and this is 2010.
This year started out as my “low key” and “quiet” GDC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>