<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GameTunnel on TooNormal</title>
    <link>https://toonormal.com/categories/gametunnel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GameTunnel on TooNormal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 04:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toonormal.com/categories/gametunnel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Snakey Jake</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/10/snakey-jake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 04:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2007/04/10/snakey-jake/</guid>
      <description>An interesting concept for design people. I&amp;rsquo;m calling them clicking platformers. Everybody&amp;rsquo;s played Wik, so I wont talk about Wik. This is a game I came across today called Snakey Jake.
Snakey Jake (YouTube Video)
It&amp;rsquo;s your usual casual game fare as far as graphics and polish are concerned. What I was expecting was a “click on a spot” sort of game and he&amp;rsquo;ll move to that spot, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually click on the platform and he&amp;rsquo;ll move to the nearest place on the platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Round-Up, and my last</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/05/26/may-round-up-and-my-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2006 02:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/05/26/may-round-up-and-my-last/</guid>
      <description>The round up for may is up. Heh, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m going to be scolded by Mike and Seth for not finding time to mention to them that this would be my last round up, but in a way, that&amp;rsquo;s half the reason why. Busy busy.
A hand full of interesting games this month. Eets, the TIM like game with the hungry mood swing guy; Bone: The Great Cow Race, a fine modern example of comic gone adventure game; Odyssey: Winds of Athena, the game with the water currents gameplay; and American History Lux, desensitizing gamers of war since 1754.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Round Up-Up</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/26/april-round-up-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 15:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/26/april-round-up-up/</guid>
      <description>Yup, I&amp;rsquo;m a few days behind mentioning this, but this month&amp;rsquo;s round up is up. A personal favorite of mine, Titan Attacks reigned supreme, followed by the slick steam powered airship game, Steam Brigade, and the un-noted but equally as surprisingly quality Inlay clone, Mosaic: Tomb of Mystery. Fun stuff.
As expected, I&amp;rsquo;m going to say things are going well with the game, despite the updates. Actually, better than well. Much Biz oriented stuff, which I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to sit on for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 ways to annoy the panel</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/06/8-ways-to-annoy-the-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2006 16:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/04/06/8-ways-to-annoy-the-panel/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve succeeded in world domination (also known as syndication), I present to you a short list of complaints to fellow developers. 8 ways to make the monthly round-up panel hate you. Unofficial in every way, as it&amp;rsquo;s just my observations, but toned a tad sarcastic and sharp to get the point across. It&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone, as we do get a good number of games that work great. But there&amp;rsquo;s just enough of them to compel me to write this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marching Round, and Up</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/20/marching-round-and-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2006 18:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/03/20/marching-round-and-up/</guid>
      <description>Yep, it&amp;rsquo;s that time of month. Tell me, what&amp;rsquo;s round, monthly and up? I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to answer that question.
A pretty light month. A slick little Final Fantasy&amp;rsquo;esc RPG, Aveyond. An adventure game with this big blue thing and a really long name, Frasse and the Peas of Kekick. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. An undersea adventure, Joust revisited, a card game, and more at the Tunnel.
Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ve been quieter than I had hoped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round and Up February</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/21/round-and-up-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2006 11:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/02/21/round-and-up-february/</guid>
      <description>Dude! There&amp;rsquo;s like, this site. And it has something to do with tunnels, or tunneling. Boy, I could tell you stories of tunneling. But they&amp;rsquo;re so amazing, they&amp;rsquo;d blow the minds of my 5 readers. The problem is I&amp;rsquo;d then have to acquire a new reader base. I can&amp;rsquo;t have that.
Right, so the more temporally correct but logically wrong February Round Up is online. Can you believe it? People mistakening the round up&amp;rsquo;s as horribly late or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December&#39;s Round Up of the Odd</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/26/decembers-round-up-of-the-odd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 06:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2006/01/26/decembers-round-up-of-the-odd/</guid>
      <description>Yes, your monthly dose of round uppage is online.
After having many great games these past few round up&amp;rsquo;s, it was expected things would cool down. This month has some cool stuff, but nothing that&amp;rsquo;s going to pull a Weird Words or such on you. The Mastermind being my favorite of the month, despite it being depressingly buggy. This followed by the funky physics motorcycle game Motorama, some addiction to Egypt with Egyptian Addiction, and a healthy dose of shooting and space games, and some Arkanoids for good measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2005 Games in Review</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/30/2005-games-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 22:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/30/2005-games-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by a discussion on Indie Gamer, and Game Tunnel&amp;rsquo;s end of year awards. Apparently it wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear, but us round up&amp;rsquo;ers were not involved in the end of year awards. So, to make up for it, I&amp;rsquo;m going to pick my favorites from the last year (December to November&amp;rsquo;s round up). I&amp;rsquo;m not going to rate them, just list them. Here we go.
MK&amp;rsquo;s 5 Indie Favorites of 2005  Weird Worlds – Oct 2005 Land of Legends – Nov 2005 UltraTron – June 2005 Mexican Motor Mafia – June 2005 Fate – July 2005  What can I say, these were all a blast to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November for Xmas</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/24/november-for-xmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 10:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/12/24/november-for-xmas/</guid>
      <description>The roundup for November is up, just in time for the big day December 25th. 10 again this time.
Many good games this month. Land of Legends, the fantasy strategy game in the top spot, followed by the wildlife park simulator Venture Africa, a hardcore space trading sim Flatspace II, an aquarium store simulator Fish Tycoon, and a slick little soccer player simulator New Star Soccer 3. Good stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Tunnels, MD</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/october-tunnels-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/11/26/october-tunnels-md/</guid>
      <description>The round up for October is up, sporting the sexah new look for the Game Tunnel website. This month sees Russell joining the ranks of the illustrious panel, bringing us to 4. It also shows us taking a more reserved 10 game count, which I think we&amp;rsquo;ll be sticking with moving forward.
So, how was the month? Two games I really liked this month, Weird Worlds and Cute Knight. Just as I said in my review, and as the others agreed, Weird Worlds is great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September Tunnel Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/20/september-tunnel-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2005 05:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/10/20/september-tunnel-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>The September Tunneling is up, and extra shiny. It was a light month, so we had to go back, and pick up a few from earlier in the year. Kisses, Zombie Smashers and Heavy Weapon being your older games. Personal favorites for this month would include The Strategist, Virus and The Goat in the Grey Fedora.
Doing the reviews like we do (blind, we don&amp;rsquo;t see each others scores until we&amp;rsquo;re all done), I always seem to have a game or two scoring regret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for August</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/tunnel-for-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2005 22:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/09/21/tunnel-for-august/</guid>
      <description>The round up is here. Hurah.
An underwater sequel to Cosmo Bots, a mech 3D shooter War World, Diablo meets Gauntlet in Evil Invasion, and a double dose of cavemen. An alright month. We&amp;rsquo;ve had better.
But wait! What is this? Bright red, black, orange and blue banners? Oh noes! What could this be? An add campaign for some wacky game? Inconceivable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for July</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/08/15/tunnel-for-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2005 19:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/08/15/tunnel-for-july/</guid>
      <description>July roundup action. Check it out here.
Some fun stuff this time. Wild Tangent&amp;rsquo;s Fate, more or less Diablo 2 with a pet. Geneforge 3, an oldskool non Japanese RPG. Facade, the crazy &amp;hellip; simulation of &amp;hellip; people &amp;hellip; with marage problems. Yeah, some really great stuff this month.
As for what&amp;rsquo;s going on, I originally ruled out the idea of actually getting something done for the IGF, but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think I can pull something together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for June</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/21/tunnel-for-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 07:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/07/21/tunnel-for-june/</guid>
      <description>Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s that time again already. Don&amp;rsquo;t look so impressed.
This was a unique month. To start, we actually recieved 11 full versions! Wow. Usually, we get anywhere from 1-3 full versions per month. This time, we had a whopping 11 (1 being freeware).
As for the games&amp;hellip; ha ha ha&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not telling you. Ok, several interesting ones. Mexican Motor Mafia was the unanimous favorite; Ultratron, Puppytron on crack; Magic Blackboard, the strangest Breakout/Arkanoid ever&amp;hellip; with “Space Gator”, as Anthony Flack put it; And finally, Summer School Girls, which was a game designed for the sole purpose of freaking me out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for May, Rant&#43;1</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/06/20/tunnel-for-may-rant1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/06/20/tunnel-for-may-rant1/</guid>
      <description>GameTunnel&amp;rsquo;s Monthly Roundup for May is up. This was apparently a tough month to find enough games. Alas, we eventually made our quota of 14. Also, this is the 12th roundup, so guess what? The roundup&amp;rsquo;s are now a year old. Spiffy. I&amp;rsquo;ve only been involved for the past 8 months, but crazy ‘ol Mike Homel&amp;rsquo;s been going strong since the beginning. Congratz.
Too Normal has been quiet this past month, but hey, I haven&amp;rsquo;t announced this site just yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunnel for April</title>
      <link>https://toonormal.com/2005/05/20/tunnel-for-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2005 01:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toonormal.com/2005/05/20/tunnel-for-april/</guid>
      <description>GameTunnel&amp;rsquo;s Monthly Roundup for April is up. Twas a good month, many cool games, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t make much of an ass of myself either. Bonus . The roundup&amp;rsquo;s have been a fun little research project of mine, gathering tactical and other information about what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world of indie gaming. Impressive enough, I just broke the 100 review barrier. I&amp;rsquo;m now sitting at 101 reviews. Wow. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; many!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>